<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Poem on un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/poem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Poem on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.125.7</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:15:35 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/poem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>20241215</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241215/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:15:35 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241215/</guid>
      <description>For Jessica, My Daughter Mark Strand (1934-2014) Tonight I walked, lost in my own meditation, and was afraid, not of the labyrinth that I have made of love and self but of the dark and faraway. I walked, hearing the wind in the trees, feeling the cold against my skin, but what I dwelled on were the stars blazing in the immense arc of sky. Jessica, it is so much easier to think of our lives, as we move under the brief luster of leaves, loving what we have, than to think of how it is such small beings as we travel in the dark with no visible way or end in sight.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>small poem</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241208/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 18:44:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241208/</guid>
      <description>John O’Donohue Fluent I would love to live Like a river flows, Carried by the surprise Of its own unfolding. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Telescope: a poem by Lousie Glück</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240724/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 18:37:14 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240724/</guid>
      <description>Telescope Telescope Louise Glück There is a moment after you move your eye away when you forget where you are because you’ve been living, it seems, somewhere else, in the silence of the night sky. You’ve stopped being here in the world. You’re in a different place, a place where human life has no meaning. You’re not a creature in body. You exist as the stars exist, participating in their stillness, their immensity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>what we are</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240718/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 09:48:49 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240718/</guid>
      <description>What We Are What we are? We say we want to become what we are or what we have an intent to be. We read the possibilities, or try. We get to some. We think we know how to read. We recognize a word, here and there, a syllable: male, it says perhaps, or female, talent - look what you could do - or love, it says, love is what we mean.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bertolt Brecht</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240405/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 10:13:21 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240405/</guid>
      <description>German
Die das Fleisch wegnehmen vom Tisch Lehren Zufriedenheit. Die, für die die Gabe bestimmt ist Verlangen Opfermut. Die Sattgefressenen sprechen zu den Hungernden Von den grossen Zeiten, die kommen werden. Die das Reich in den Abgrund führen Nennen das Regieren zu schwer Für den einfachen Mann. English Translation:
Those Who Take the Meat from the Table Teach Contentment. Those for whom the taxes are destined Demand sacrifice. Those who eat their fill speak to the hungry Of wonderful times to come.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20240222</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240222/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 14:07:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240222/</guid>
      <description>子曰：“笃信好学，守死善道。危邦不入，乱邦不居。天下有道则见，无道则隐。邦有道，贫且贱焉，耻也；邦无道，富且贵焉，耻也。”
半轮秋月挂山崖，孤鸟悲鸣为有家。一己哀愁随落叶，百年世事入残霞。2022.10.2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shoveling snow with buddha</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240106/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 14:18:24 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240106/</guid>
      <description>Shoveling Snow With Buddha Billy Collins
In the usual iconography of the temple or the local Wok you would never see him doing such a thing, tossing the dry snow over a mountain of his bare, round shoulder, his hair tied in a knot, a model of concentration.
Sitting is more his speed, if that is the word for what he does, or does not do.
Even the season is wrong for him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>weekly notes</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221126/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 20:09:14 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221126/</guid>
      <description>Green Koan by Rita Dove That the mind can go wherever it wishes is a kindness we&amp;rsquo;ve come to rely on; that it returns unbidden to the soul it could not banish and learns to thrive there is life&amp;rsquo;s stubborn mercy &amp;ndash; given to soften or harden us, as we choose.
Code is the biggest lever humanity has ever invented From Amjad Masad:
Code is the biggest lever humanity has ever invented.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mayakovsky</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221105/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 12:25:39 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221105/</guid>
      <description>Mayakovsky BY FRANK O&amp;#39;HARA 1 My heart’s aflutter! I am standing in the bath tub crying. Mother, mother who am I? If he will just come back once and kiss me on the face his coarse hair brush my temple, it’s throbbing! then I can put on my clothes I guess, and walk the streets. 2 I love you. I love you, but I’m turning to my verses and my heart is closing like a fist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Postcards</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220611/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 09:28:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220611/</guid>
      <description>Black Postcards I
The calendar all booked up, the future unknown. The cable silently hums some folk song but lacks a country. Snow falls in the grey sea. Shadows fight out on the dock.
II
Halfway through my life, death turns up and takes your pertinent measurements. We forget the visit. Life goes on. But someone is sewing the suit in the silence.
I hear my country in your voice From Romeo Oriogun:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emily Dickinson</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20211212/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 14:34:21 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20211212/</guid>
      <description>In this short Life that only lasts an hour
How much - how little - is within our power</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
