<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>albert camus on un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/albert-camus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in albert camus on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.3</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 07:34:07 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/albert-camus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>notes on 20240919</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240919/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 07:34:07 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240919/</guid>
      <description>lung-gom-pa You must be curious about what lung-gom-pa is. It is an ecstatic state: running in a trance, just like lungs-on-legs.
Albert Camus: In the depth of winter I learned that there lay within me an invincible summer.
Albert Camus: what if Sisyphus is happy? La lutte elle-même vers les sommets suffit à remplir un cœur d&amp;rsquo;homme; il faut imaginer Sisyphe heureux. The struggle itself towards the summit is enough to fill a man&amp;rsquo;s heart; you have to imagine Sisyphus happy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>But you need to breathe. And you need to be.</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240322/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 10:55:13 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240322/</guid>
      <description>Albert Camus, Notebooks 1951-1959
Find meaning. Distinguish melancholy from sadness. Go out for a walk. It doesn’t have to be a romantic walk in the park, spring at its most spectacular moment, flowers and smells and outstanding poetical imagery smoothly transferring you into another world. It doesn’t have to be a walk during which you’ll have multiple life epiphanies and discover meanings no other brain ever managed to encounter. Do not be afraid of spending quality time by yourself.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
