<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>life on un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 07:53:38 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>what is you?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230726/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 07:53:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230726/</guid>
      <description>There is going to have the first Dark ID (DID) design. The idea of DID dwelled in my mind for about two years. Now I can finally see its form. I am not sure how others receive it but it&amp;rsquo;s mine, unique to what I am.
This reminds me of one thing that Jorge Borges said in Spanish. &amp;ldquo;Sólo perduran en el tiempo las cosas Que no fueron del tiempo.&amp;rdquo; After translation, it is roughly as follows: Only things that were not of time endure in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half a story</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220420/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 12:05:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220420/</guid>
      <description>I have been to several cities in my travel.
I lived in a city when I was young. In the north, there&amp;rsquo;s my childhood in a rural village and a high school. In the east, that&amp;rsquo;s my home for a while. In the west, I had my best college time. In the south, that&amp;rsquo;s where my girlfriend lived. At that time, the city was still small. I could walk to my grandma&amp;rsquo;s house on my little feet from my school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fish and Pond</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220306/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 14:38:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220306/</guid>
      <description>Think of your mind like a pond full of fish and each fish is a feeling. Try to be the pond, not the fish.
Life is nothing but time given to us, short or long. For all of us, a day is long and a year is short. We use our days to trade for years. We trade our time for food, clothes, houses and cars. In the end, time is the only thing we do not have.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
