<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ukraine on un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/ukraine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ukraine on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.146.7</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 15:40:14 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/ukraine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>a part of power: you and me</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231124/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 15:40:14 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231124/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of people will side with the power to survive, not the truth, not the beauty, not the kids because the society is structured with power. I have to say that there are definitely a few exceptions out there. They are the light in the darkness and the hope out of desperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 31, 2023 at online Bucha Summit, Secretary Blinken commented as follow: &amp;ldquo;One year ago today, when Ukrainian forces liberated Bucha, they discovered a massacre.  Hundreds of men, women, and children killed indiscriminately by Russian forces.&amp;rdquo; So Blinken is talking about to hold Russia accountable for its war crime in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The despair of Ukraine and others</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230629/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 13:43:19 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230629/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.politico.eu/article/ukraine-drowning-in-despair-nova-kakhovka-dam-destruction-war-russia-united-nations/&#34;&gt;one commentary&lt;/a&gt; on politico.eu on Ukraine by Mariam Naiem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 6, a catastrophic event unfolded in Ukraine as the dam in Nova Kakhovka was destroyed, another war crime by Russia. I&amp;rsquo;d like to highlight the following paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To us (Ukrainians), it feels as though the world is anticipating yet another tragedy, as if we are simply characters in a dystopian series. Only when faced with a concoction of pandemics, floods, bombings, torture and rape can we receive help and support. And not only this, but we have to repeatedly prove to the audience that we are brave, honest, “civilized” and not wasteful. Prove again and again that no, we are not Nazis — contrary to what Russian President Vladimir Putin has claimed. When making a moral case for support, that we are not irrational or too emotional.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solidarity with Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220417/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 13:16:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220417/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is unreal to watch some alleged leftists, in real time, fail to recognise a fascist dictatorship attempting to exterminate a liberal democracy, and calling for that democracy to surrender to fascism in the name of peace.&amp;rdquo; I am with Oz Katerji on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we agree Hitler invaded Poland, we have to agree Putin invaded Ukraine. If we stand with Ukraine, we have to send all resources including food, medcine, and arms to help Ukraine to defend themselves, till the victorious end. There is no other choices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Noam Chomsky Interview</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220406/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:50:52 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220406/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the age of 93, Chomsky told us, &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re approaching the most dangerous point in human history &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s monstrous for Ukraine.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It’s certainly right to have moral outrage about Putin’s actions in Ukraine,” he said of Biden’s recent declaration that the Russian president “cannot remain in power”. “But it would be even more progress to have moral outrage about other horrible atrocities… In Afghanistan, literally millions of people are facing imminent starvation. Why? There’s food in the markets. But people who have little money have to watch their children starve because they can’t go to the market to buy food. Why? Because the United States, with the backing of Britain, has kept Afghanistan’s funds in New York banks and will not release them.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invasion!</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220221/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 14:55:05 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220221/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today Putin ordered troops into pro-Russian region of eastern Ukraine in the name of peacekeeping. Ukraine invaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I saw the news of Dr. Paul Farmer. “The idea that some lives matter less is the root of all that is wrong with the world.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
