<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 10:39:22 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>旧作重读</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220425/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 10:39:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220425/</guid>
      <description>“人造之物皆有生命。”记不得是在哪里看到这段话，“语言自然而生，文化随之而来。建房修葺，修路搭桥，这些不都是生命的延展？学校教堂医院，警局政府法院，这些不都是生命的附属？“</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derrida&#39;s Deconstruction</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220423/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 13:49:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220423/</guid>
      <description>Michael Peterson Is his writing difficult? I suppose so, in the sense that it uses a technical vocabulary specific to his work and the tradition he is working from. These are, most basically: phenomenology, semiotics, psychoanalysis, and Western philosophical history.
Combined, this leaves us in a position where the objects of his inquiry are varied and risk being construed as overly general. He writes about ethics, politics, language, time, space, forgiveness, the death penalty, sovereignty, Marxism, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>乌克兰和上海</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220422/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 16:24:39 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220422/</guid>
      <description>峰峦如聚，波涛如怒，山河表里潼关路。望西都，意踟蹰。 伤心秦汉经行处，宫阙万间都做了土。兴，百姓苦；亡，百姓苦。
在我们这儿新冠疫情早在三月就结束了。到现在新冠已经有六波了，不过因为有mRNA疫苗的保护（大多数人都接种了三针）一切也算是正常。口罩还有人戴，公共交通还要求戴，其它场所就是自愿的了。现在的新闻主要就是乌克兰和上海。
俄罗斯入侵乌克兰已经50多天了，国内有不少人竟然说，俄罗斯入侵乌克兰是因为北约东扩，并以此为俄罗斯的侵略战争辩护。如果二战时希特勒入侵波兰是侵略，当年美国进攻伊拉克是侵略，为什么普京入侵乌克兰就不是侵略？站在俄罗斯那些邻国的角度，为什么那些国家要或者想要加入北约？不就是担心俄罗斯的威胁。而这次俄罗斯的入侵更证明了这些担心并非空穴来风。再说了，俄罗斯为什么不想那些邻国加入北约？不就是担心人民自己选择的自由会威胁或动摇独裁专制。对乌克兰的真正支持只有一种，那就是提供各种支援，包括食物、药品和武器弹药，支持乌克兰保家卫国，直到最后的胜利。
上海这个两千五百万人口的大都市因为奥密克戎而封城，由此引发各种惨剧。许多人没有受到新冠影响，却承受了封城的苦难。有人在家挨饿，有人急症得不到救治，有人不堪重负跳楼自尽。大白和红马甲却享受了至高权力的威风，以防疫之名可以随意殴打、抓捕，擅闯民宅。美领馆撤了，日本领馆没吃的了，韩国领事致函复旦请求让韩国留学生回国。一个国际大都市为什么会变成这样？武汉封城，西安封城，深圳封城，同样的悲剧为什么要一次次重复上演？难道润是普通百姓的唯一选择？</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half a story</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220420/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 12:05:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220420/</guid>
      <description>I have been to several cities in my travel.
I lived in a city when I was young. In the north, there&amp;rsquo;s my childhood in a rural village and a high school. In the east, that&amp;rsquo;s my home for a while. In the west, I had my best college time. In the south, that&amp;rsquo;s where my girlfriend lived. At that time, the city was still small. I could walk to my grandma&amp;rsquo;s house on my little feet from my school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solidarity with Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220417/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 13:16:03 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220417/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;It is unreal to watch some alleged leftists, in real time, fail to recognise a fascist dictatorship attempting to exterminate a liberal democracy, and calling for that democracy to surrender to fascism in the name of peace.&amp;rdquo; I am with Oz Katerji on this.
If we agree Hitler invaded Poland, we have to agree Putin invaded Ukraine. If we stand with Ukraine, we have to send all resources including food, medcine, and arms to help Ukraine to defend themselves, till the victorious end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do we really love?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220415/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 10:17:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220415/</guid>
      <description>Went hiking to a nearby park. Bit cold and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty soon that my face was numbed. Birds sang their morning songs with no stop. On the top, the white peaks of rocky mountians in the west are clear to see. But no one to see but birds.
Memory is clearly somewhere in our brain. When we remember something, it&amp;rsquo;s somehow printed hard there. If you practise, anything like jogging, swimming, basketball, guitar, violin, or piano, you know how the muscle memory is there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Half of a Story</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220411/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 16:04:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220411/</guid>
      <description>I still do not know what is the best way to say goodbye. I hate it. So all the time, I evaded them because they were sad. Upon graduation, I did not send my friends off. Leaving my hometown, I left alone. No one taught me, I just tried it out slowly as life moves on. I have so many things to say. But where to start?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>double standard</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220410/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 14:03:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220410/</guid>
      <description>Double standard is everywhere in our life. The difference between I and others. The difference between my family and others. The difference between my people and others.
President Zelensky is leading a fight not only for defending Ukraine but the freedom of western values. He is a hero. But if we are serious, we have to deal with the double standard. Besides Kyiv, how about other cities like Baghdad, or Kabul?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Noam Chomsky Interview</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220406/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:50:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220406/</guid>
      <description>At the age of 93, Chomsky told us, &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re approaching the most dangerous point in human history &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s monstrous for Ukraine.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;It’s certainly right to have moral outrage about Putin’s actions in Ukraine,” he said of Biden’s recent declaration that the Russian president “cannot remain in power”. “But it would be even more progress to have moral outrage about other horrible atrocities… In Afghanistan, literally millions of people are facing imminent starvation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another C Code Joke</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220327/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 14:07:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220327/</guid>
      <description>$ pcat goes-to.c #include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt; int main() { int x = 5; // while x goes to 0:  while (x --&amp;gt; 0) { printf(&amp;#34;%d &amp;#34;, x); } printf(&amp;#34;\n&amp;#34;); return 0; } $ gcc goes-to.c &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ./a.out 4 3 2 1 0 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Freud&#39;s single greatest contribution?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220323/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 20:04:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220323/</guid>
      <description>Freud already answered this question, of course, when he said that whereas Darwin decentered the human animal from the apex of creation, Copernicus decentered the earth from the center of the universe, Freud had decentered humanity in itself. No longer was the human immanent.
Lacan&amp;rsquo;s answer is perhaps even better: &amp;ldquo;That is why the unconscious was invented—so that we would realize that man&amp;rsquo;s desire is the Other&amp;rsquo;s desire, and that love, while it is a passion that involves ignorance of desire, nevertheless leaves desire its whole import&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebuild</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/rebuild/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 15:16:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/rebuild/</guid>
      <description>how to build this hugo site</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Code Jokes</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220318/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 15:22:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220318/</guid>
      <description>Here are some C code with the JavaScript quirks. Credits to luna.
#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt; int main() { puts(&amp;#34;-0.5&amp;#34; + 1); printf(&amp;#34;%d\n&amp;#34;, 50 ** &amp;#34;2&amp;#34;); return 0; } To build and run the above code, just do the following and ignore the warnings.
$ gcc c-js.c &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ./a.out 0.5 2500 Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the warnings first.
c-js.c:4:15: warning: adding &amp;#39;int&amp;#39; to a string does not append to the string [-Wstring-plus-int] puts(&amp;#34;-0.5&amp;#34; + 1); ~~~~~~~^~~ c-js.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fish and Pond</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220306/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 14:38:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220306/</guid>
      <description>Think of your mind like a pond full of fish and each fish is a feeling. Try to be the pond, not the fish.
Life is nothing but time given to us, short or long. For all of us, a day is long and a year is short. We use our days to trade for years. We trade our time for food, clothes, houses and cars. In the end, time is the only thing we do not have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toit Imports</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220303/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 14:44:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220303/</guid>
      <description>Toitlang uses import to use code from other libraries.
 local import starting with .  $ tree . └── my_lib ├── my_lib.toit ├── other.toit └── sub └── sub.toit Assume we are importing sub.toit into my_lib.toit.
import .sub.sub Shorten version:
import .sub  global import  import math Then for customizations,
import math as m import math show sin cos </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cron is fun</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220302/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 14:21:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220302/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Toit Code (002)</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220301/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 14:47:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220301/</guid>
      <description>After toit_start(), we have toit_esp32.cc to read. The first one is toit::start(). Toit here is just a namespace. As we know that toit supports OTA (over-the-air update) through WiFi and esp32 device is set to be a station (STA instead of AP).
What we have here is as follows:
 RtcMemory::set_up(); FlashRegistry::set_up(); OS::set_up(); esp_partition_find_first(); setup_program(support_ota); Scheduler::ExitState exit_state; VM vm; vm.load_platform_event_sources(); int groud_id = vm.scheduler()-&amp;gt;next_group_id(); exit_state = vm.scheduler()-&amp;gt;run_boot_program(program, null, group_id); OS::tear_down(); FlashRegistry::tear_down();  After these, esp32 may go to deep sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Toit Code (001)</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220225/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:51:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220225/</guid>
      <description>When I started to port the code to ESP32S3 following the example of ESP32C3, I realized I had to read the code closely. Here are the notes along the way.
Where does the code get started on esp32? Based on esp-idf, Toit (I like to pronounce it as tight) creates a new platform with a new programming language for developers.
For the code to start on the esp32 device, check all the files inside toolchains/esp32/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invasion!</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220221/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 14:55:05 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220221/</guid>
      <description>Today Putin ordered troops into pro-Russian region of eastern Ukraine in the name of peacekeeping. Ukraine invaded.
Then I saw the news of Dr. Paul Farmer. “The idea that some lives matter less is the root of all that is wrong with the world.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infinite Dead</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220204/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 14:57:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220204/</guid>
      <description>I remember once offering to an editor an article which began with a reference to the experience of last century. “Oh,” he said, “leave out the history and come to the present.” I felt like going to him over a thousand miles and taking him by the lapels and saying, “Dear, dear jackass! Don’t you understand that the past is the present; that without what was, nothing is? That, of the infinite dead, the living are but unimportant bits?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do not ask your children</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220203/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 14:59:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220203/</guid>
      <description>Do not ask your children
to strive for extraordinary lives.
Such striving may seem admirable,
but it is the way of foolishness.
Help them instead to find the wonder
and the marvel of an ordinary life.
Show them the joy of tasting
tomatoes, apples and pears.
Show them how to cry
when pets and people die.
Show them the infinite pleasure
in the touch of a hand.
And make the ordinary come alive for them</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reading experience</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220129/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 15:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220129/</guid>
      <description>“People without hope not only don’t write novels, but what is more to the point, they don’t read them. They don’t take long looks at anything, because they lack the courage. The way to despair is to refuse to have any kind of experience, and the novel, of course, is a way to have experience. The lady who only read books that improved her mind was taking a safe course - and a hopeless one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mindful and calm</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220125/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 15:03:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220125/</guid>
      <description>The good and the bad are everywhere all the time. While reading stories and watching movies there are always heroes and villains in these endless dramas. There are always Don Quixote and Sancho. What am I? What are you? A mixture of good and bad. That’s all. What if we stop dividing us into black and white?
  One teaching of Budha is now and here. What does it mean?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Jaguar to update</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220117/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 15:05:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220117/</guid>
      <description>Use an Airport to setup a WiFi network. Then download the binary of Jaguar. Run the following commands one after another. The second command requires the WiFi credentials. Use CTRL+C to stop the third one. To run the forth and the fifth command, put your computer on the same WiFi network as the esp32 device.
$./jag setup $./jag flash $./jag monitor $./jag scan $./jag run hello.toit </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wasm3 on esp32</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220116/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 15:11:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220116/</guid>
      <description>Stumbled on this repo.
Run the modified code on one snowflake with 25 RGB LEDs (ws2812b-2020).
Check the video tweet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toit on m5core2</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220115/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 15:13:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220115/</guid>
      <description>Build some examples in toit and flash it to M5Core2.
There is no problem to follow the steps in one toit discussion. While trying the step4 for ft63xx. Found a typo in package.yaml. mpu6886 should be ft63xx.
Another issue is that the touch seems not working after unplugging the USB cable. Will investigate further. Will try jaguar tool later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust on esp32</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220111/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 15:18:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220111/</guid>
      <description>Start to look at the toolchain for Rust on ESP32 family modules. After some googling, here is the first result.
Clearly the toolchain is working in its early stage. $ cargo build OK. Both espflash and espmonitor are working.
Reference:
 Rust on ESP32 rust esp32 std demo  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mass delusion</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220108/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 15:23:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220108/</guid>
      <description>“Of special importance is the case in which substantial numbers of people, acting in concert, try to assure themselves of happiness and protection against suffering through a delusional reshaping of reality. The religions of mankind too must be described as example of mass delusion. Of course, no one who still shares a delusion will ever recognize it as such.”
“We never have so little protection against suffering as when we are in love; we are never so desolate when we have lost the object of our love or its love for us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I write</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20211224/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 15:24:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20211224/</guid>
      <description>Had my credentials been in order I would never have become a writer. Had I been blessed with even limited access to my own mind there would have been no reason to write. I write entirely to find out what I’m thinking, what I’m looking at, what I see and what it means. What I want and what I fear. Why did the oil refineries around Carquinez Strait seem sinister to me in the summer of 1956?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emily Dickinson</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20211212/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 14:34:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20211212/</guid>
      <description>In this short Life that only lasts an hour
How much - how little - is within our power</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
