<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.125.7</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 14:47:21 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enron trader and quantitative research</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250215/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 14:47:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250215/</guid>
      <description>Enron was founded by Kenneth Lay in 1985 in Houston, Texas. It started in energy, commodities and services. The company filed for bankruptcy on Dec 2, 2001 while employing about 20,600 staff with a revenue of $100B in 2000. Enron scandal was the biggest audit failure.
John Arnold was born in 1974 and growed up in Dallas Texas. He graduated in 1995 from Vanderbilt University with a degree in math and economics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>how venture capital works</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250210/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 11:42:55 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250210/</guid>
      <description>how VC works? where VCs get their money, a high-risk asset? The job of fund managers is to ensure that giant pile of money grows. At the lowest end, it needs to grow in line with inflation, 9% annually in US for example.
VC is spread-betting across a large number of startuos. They are trying to deploy a fund into a set of startups that matches their hopes, dreams and ambitions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>some quotes on truth, time, and others</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250207/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 10:26:23 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250207/</guid>
      <description>“Only those who have the patience to do simple things perfectly will acquire the skill to do difficult things easily.” – Friedrich Schiller
“The truth is generally seen, rarely heard.” – Baltasar Gracian
“Conquer yourself rather than the world.” – Rene Descartes
“One should use common words to say uncommon things.” – Arthur Schopenhauer
“Hang on to your youthful enthusiasms – you’ll be able to use them better when you’re older.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20250206</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250206/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 13:23:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250206/</guid>
      <description>How to use an captcha image as a sing-in and verification button without JavaScript? &amp;lt;input_type=&amp;#34;image&amp;#34;&amp;gt; this image supplements the &amp;lt;input type=&amp;quot;submit&amp;quot;&amp;gt; element. Click the image submits the form with two query parameters included: ?x=32&amp;amp;y=48. Using CSRF tokens, the server knows where it put your open circle.
Other sites implement the Captcha in other creative ways. One uses an &amp;lt;input type=&amp;quot;range&amp;quot;&amp;gt; to position an image to the correct place.
The most impressive one uses a series of checkboxes positioned in the exact same place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20250201</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250201/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 14:37:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250201/</guid>
      <description>当一个人口众多的国家，个人行动全凭儒家简单粗浅而又无法固定的原则所限制，而法律又缺乏创造性，则其社会发展的程度，必然受到限制。即便是宗旨善良，也不能补助技术之不及。1587年，是为万历十五年，丁亥次岁，表面上似乎是四海升平，无事可记，实际上我们的大明帝国却已经走到了它发展的尽头。在这个时候，皇帝的励精图治或者宴安耽乐，首辅的独裁或者调和，高级将领的富于创造或者习于苟安，文官的廉洁奉公或者贪污舞弊，思想家的极端进步或者绝对保守，最后的结果，都是无分善恶，统统不能在事业上取得有意义的发展，有的身败，有的名裂，还有的人则身败而兼名裂。因此我们的故事只好在这里作悲剧性的结束。万历丁亥年的年鉴，是为历史上一部失败的总记录。《万历十五年》
在美国读书和打工时，我常被在中国的痛苦回忆所折磨，不时陷入沉思。后来当教师，拿着麦克风站在五百名大学生面前，无法立即解释：为何康有为失败了，孙中山失败了，袁世凯失败了，张作霖失败了，陈独秀失败了，蒋介石失败了，而毛泽东也失败了。为使我的讲课内容前后一致又有说服力，唯一的方法就是说，中国的问题大于上述人士努力的总和。中国文明将和西方文明融合的说法，是人类历史上空前的事件。上述不同阶段的失败必须被视为阶段的调试，以达成一致的终点。对我们这些有后见之识的人来说，这点很明显，但舞台上的演员看不到。《黄河青山》
Notes:
The tariff announced by Trump admin was a &amp;ldquo;trump tax&amp;rdquo; on Canada, Mexico, and China. The only thing left is to fight this bully to the end.
“严沧浪云：‘诗有别才，非关书也；诗有别趣，非关理也；然非多读书，多穷理，则不能极其至。’卓哉是言乎。&amp;quot; 诗，AI 可以解读评论，却难创作。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critique of Marx&#39;s Capital by Robert Wolff</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250125/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 12:19:20 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250125/</guid>
      <description>video the thought of Marx lecture01 Jan 15, 2011 lecture02 Jan 16, 2011 lecture03 Jan 17, 2011 lecture04 Jan 19, 2011 lecture05 Jan 24, 2011 lecture06 2011 lecture07 2011 the thought of Karl Marx part 10, Jan 28, 2011 blog
Karl Marx (1818-1883): the theorist of capitalism, the historian of economic theory, a great economic theorist. dialectical materialism was Engel&amp;rsquo;s idea.
Analytical Marxists:
Gerald Cohen, KARL MARX&amp;rsquo;S THEORY OF HISTORY, Jan Elster, MAKING SENSE OF MARX Robert Wolff: Marx considers the philosophy of a society to be a part of its ideological superstructure, along with its religion, law, and art, among other things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 lists</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250121/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 16:55:22 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250121/</guid>
      <description>book list Time Shelter, Georgi Gospodinov, Translated by Angela Rodel 回忆反而导致失忆，时间在避难所中逐渐失去意义
The Talented Mr. Ripley, Patricia Highsmith
Technofeudalism, Yanis Varoufakis, 2023
Tim O&amp;rsquo;Brien, The things they carried, 1990
web links and sw tools video transcoder: https://handbrake.fr/
youtube video downloader: https://github.com/soimort/you-get (cmd in python)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>reading and others</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250116/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:02:25 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250116/</guid>
      <description>our real work Our real work Wendell Berry, 1983 It may be that when we no longer know what to do We have come to our real work, And that when we no longer know which way to go We have come to our real journey. The mind that is not baffled is not employed. The impeded stream is the one that sings. the following is all about reading &amp;ldquo;If you think about it, the very best books are really just extremely long spells that turn you into a different person for the rest of your life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20250112</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250112/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:59:06 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250112/</guid>
      <description>The New Song by W. S. Merwin For some time I thought there was time and that there would always be time for what I had a mind to do and what I could imagine going back to and finding it as I had found it the first time but by this time I do not know what I thought when I thought back then there is no time yet it grows less there is the sound of rain at night arriving unknown in the leaves once without before or after then I hear the thrush waking at daybreak singing the new song </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kant Critique of pure reason by Robert Paul wolff</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250108/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:36:27 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250108/</guid>
      <description>Start to read the blog of Robert Paul wolff. Start to watch his lectures on Kant.
video blog part 1 Reading the Critique Part I part 2 reading the Critique Part II part 3 reading the Critique Part III part 4 reading the Critique part IV part 5 reading the Critique part V part 6 reading the Critique part VI part 7 reading the Critique part VII part 8 reading the critique part VIII part 9 reading the Critique part IX From the wiki page: Kant builds on the work of empiricist philosophers such as John Locke and David Hume, as well as rationalist philosophers such as Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz and Christian Wolff.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>poems from anne sexton</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250102/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:58:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250102/</guid>
      <description>As it has been said: Love and a cough cannot be concealed. Even a small cough. Even a small love. Words and eggs must be handled with care. Once broken they are impossible things to repair. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Henry Ford&#39;s Quotes</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241231/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:18:11 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241231/</guid>
      <description>Came across several quotes from Henry Ford:
Money doesn’t change men, it merely unmasks them. If a man is naturally selfish or arrogant or greedy, the money brings that out.
Wealth, like happiness, is never attained when sought after directly. It comes as a by-product of providing a useful service.
The best way to make money is to stop thinking about making money and start thinking about serving people.
The greatest thing in life is to keep your mind young.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mind or heart</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241228/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:09:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241228/</guid>
      <description>We don’t see things as they are, we see them as we are.
A mind not to be changed by place or time. The mind is its own place, and in itself Can make a heav’n of hell, a hell of heav’n. John Milton (1608-1674), Paradise Lost In books we never find anything but ourselves. Strangely enough, that always gives us great pleasure, and we say the author is a genius.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>poems</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241222/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 19:50:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241222/</guid>
      <description>Separation W.S.Merwin Your absence has gone through me Like thread through a needle Everything i do is stitched with its color Some people feel the rain. Others just get wet. -- Bob Marley </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20241215</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241215/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:15:35 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241215/</guid>
      <description>For Jessica, My Daughter Mark Strand (1934-2014) Tonight I walked, lost in my own meditation, and was afraid, not of the labyrinth that I have made of love and self but of the dark and faraway. I walked, hearing the wind in the trees, feeling the cold against my skin, but what I dwelled on were the stars blazing in the immense arc of sky. Jessica, it is so much easier to think of our lives, as we move under the brief luster of leaves, loving what we have, than to think of how it is such small beings as we travel in the dark with no visible way or end in sight.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>small poem</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241208/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 18:44:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241208/</guid>
      <description>John O’Donohue Fluent I would love to live Like a river flows, Carried by the surprise Of its own unfolding. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20241130</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241130/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 15:43:50 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241130/</guid>
      <description>Hell is empty and all the devils are here. William Shakespeare, The Tempest Some believe it is only great power that can hold evil in check, but that is not what I have found. It is the small everyday deeds of ordinary folk that keep the darkness at bay. Small acts of kindness and love. J.R.R.Tolkien, The Hobbit, 1937.
But imprint this on your mind: tolerance becomes a crime when applied to evil.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be yourself is the best you could hope</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241115/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:44:31 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241115/</guid>
      <description>Read a story from Daring Fireball. The story has two parts. The first half is about his mother&amp;rsquo;s death starting from May this year. The second half is about his father and his wedding ring. The whole story adds flavor with this election. You know, Bob Gruber, his father is an optimist at heart.
Waves in an impossible Sea by Matt Strassler: You and I are small, so we think light runs like a rabbit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>some quotes from Carl Sagan</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241110/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 14:52:39 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241110/</guid>
      <description>The Earth is a very small stage in a vast cosmic arena. Think of the endless cruelties visited by the inhabitants of one corner of this pixel on the scarcely distinguishable inhabitants of some other corner, how frequent their misunderstandings, how eager they are to kill one another, how fervent their hatreds. Think of the rivers of blood spilled by all those generals and emperors so that, in glory and triumph, they could become the momentary masters of a fraction of a dot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20241106</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241106/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 11:02:43 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241106/</guid>
      <description>Albert Camus: “Every time I hear a political speech or I read those of our leaders, I am horrified at having, for years, heard nothing which sounded human. It is always the same words telling the same lies. And the fact that men accept this, that the people’s anger has not destroyed these hollow clowns, strikes me as proof that men attribute no importance to the way they are governed; that they gamble – yes, gamble – with a whole part of their life and their so called &amp;lsquo;vital interests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>facts, reality, languages and cultures</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241031/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 10:27:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241031/</guid>
      <description>Timothy Snyder, On Tyranny: To abandon facts is to abandon freedom. If nothing is true, then all is spectacle. The biggest wallet pays for the most blinding lights.
Marcek Proust, In Search of Lost Time: We construct our lives for one person, and when at length it is ready to receive her that person does not come; presently she is dead to us, and we live on, prisoners within the walls which were intended only for her.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>cheese bread and the market</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 12:08:36 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241025/</guid>
      <description>cheese bread Made some cheese bread. the dough has a bit of cheese. the crust is thin with olive oil applied at the top. A little salt to add favor. Then a layer of cheese on the top. Bake it to golden top. You have a crusty top and edge with layered and soft internals.
Cem Karsan on market volatility He build his models to profit on the volatility of the market.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes on mental breakthroughs</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 14:05:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241019/</guid>
      <description>As we became more experienced, it&amp;rsquo;s harder to get or feel a breakthrough. However, once you get it, it is so exciting. The context here is that I am thinking about Buddhism for quite a long time (心外无别法). Then when you connect it with philosophy, say German idealists such as Kant and Hegel, it becomes clear that our ideas and minds is very important to shape and understand the reality. This has no conflict with scientific truth from materialism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hegelian Dialectics</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241004/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 10:35:28 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20241004/</guid>
      <description>dialectics Kant: Kant’s critical philosophy utilized dialectics to challenge metaphysical claims and to propose that reality is shaped by our perceptions.
German idealists: Fichte, Schelling, and Hegel further developed this idea, using dialectics to delve into the nature of being and knowledge itself. Hegel’s dialectic, in particular, is famous for its thesis-antithesis-synthesis progression.
Thesis: A proposition or an idea is put forward, starting the dialectical process. Antithesis: This initial idea is then countered with an opposing view or critique.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Helene, Mideast and others</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240929/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 13:24:58 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240929/</guid>
      <description>Helene reached the small town of Spruce Pine, North Carolina, which is home to the purest natural quartz on Earth. The quartz is used as a crucible to melt polysilicon, which is then used to produce silicon wafers - the base of semiconductor manufacturing. There are two mining companies there, Quartz Corp and Sibelco.
Zygmunt Bauman (1925-2017)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes on 20240919</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240919/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 07:34:07 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240919/</guid>
      <description>lung-gom-pa You must be curious about what lung-gom-pa is. It is an ecstatic state: running in a trance, just like lungs-on-legs.
Albert Camus: In the depth of winter I learned that there lay within me an invincible summer.
Albert Camus: what if Sisyphus is happy? La lutte elle-même vers les sommets suffit à remplir un cœur d&amp;rsquo;homme; il faut imaginer Sisyphe heureux. The struggle itself towards the summit is enough to fill a man&amp;rsquo;s heart; you have to imagine Sisyphus happy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>who win?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240911/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 20:01:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240911/</guid>
      <description>Hope it will be proved wrong in the due time. The source is from Kate Manne.
Three types of programming:
PS 2024-10-06 it is a year now. the longer the war by Isreal, the less chance of Harris to win. it is unfortunate but that is exactly what Democratic Party is doing now. then it will blame voters for its failure. The Hamas attack last year is terrorism. The war in Gaza by Isreal is genocide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology: MS and ESS</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240908/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 08:18:16 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240908/</guid>
      <description>Changes in assumptions:
modern synthesis extended evolutionary synthesis the pre-eminance of natural selection reciprocal causation (organisms shape, and shaped by, selective and developmental environments) genetic inheritance inclusive inheritance random genetic variation non-random phenotypic variation gradualism variable rates of change gene-centred perspective organism-centred perspective micro-evolution macro-evolution For classical MS, the major directing or creative influence in evolution is natural selection, which alone explains why the properties of organisms match the properties of their environments (adaptation).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rustup</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240907/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 09:56:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240907/</guid>
      <description>Update rust
$ rustc --version rustc 1.78.0 (9b00956e5 2024-04-29) $ rustup update $ rustc --version rustc 1.81.0 (eeb90cda1 2024-09-04) Start to play with Tauri: node.js + rust =&amp;gt; GUI App. There are examples of deno and tauri.
Another interesting thing is WebUI in C with WebSocket, that uses browser as the GUI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the world versus me</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240906/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 06:39:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240906/</guid>
      <description>This is from a tweet: knowing about architecture means buildings are legible in a different way; knowing about plants and birds makes hikes more stimulating, playing music makes listening to it richer, etc.
However, it clicks with me from another perspective. To understand or to know the world better, we have to know some details and have to know it in one or many more abstracted ways. Yes, the world (so vast in both time and space) to us (so tiny, life is so short) is always abstracted one way or another for us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Days at the Morisaki Bookshop</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240902/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 18:39:35 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240902/</guid>
      <description>Once night fell, it turned thoroughly cold out. I wrapped my scarf tighter around my neck. My uncle was grumbling beside me, his breath making hazy white puffs that hung in the air for a moment and then vanished into the night.
what is gone with these white puffs?
I could see in the courtyard on the other side of the hospital window that early cherry blossoms had already started to fall.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>do real things</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240830/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 13:52:50 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240830/</guid>
      <description>Business owners spend more time printing business cards than finding clients. People trying to get in shape who buy fancy workout gear instead of exercising. Pretend activity instead of the real thing.
Ask questions and find the real pain and problems to solve.
Real things have risk. They have the possibility of failure. They have frustration. They force you to confront the possibility that maybe you just aren’t good enough. Fake activity is great for making yourself feel better, but lousy for actual results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20240824</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240824/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 10:26:19 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240824/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Stories – frankly, human stories are always about one thing – death. The inevitability of death.&amp;rdquo;
He then read aloud from that article, which quoted from Simone de Beauvoir&amp;rsquo;s A Very Easy Death, her moving 1964 account of her mother&amp;rsquo;s desire to cling to life during her dying days. &amp;ldquo;There is no such thing as a natural death,&amp;rdquo; he read. &amp;ldquo;Nothing that happens to a man is ever natural, since his presence calls the world into question.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes on 2024-08-22</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240822/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 09:45:47 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240822/</guid>
      <description>Bash scripting
intro to CPU
AI to separate lyrics, chords and melody
duckDB as a command line tool
duckDB</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keep fun in computing</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240816/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 13:10:46 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240816/</guid>
      <description>This book is dedicated, in respect and admiration, to the spirit that lives in the computer.
“I think that it’s extraordinarily important that we in computer science keep fun in computing. When it started out, it was an awful lot of fun. Of course, the paying customers got shafted every now and then, and after a while we began to take their complaints seriously. We began to feel as if we really were responsible for the successful, error-free perfect use of these machines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>picotool for RP2040</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240806/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 10:08:08 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240806/</guid>
      <description>There are many RP2040 dev boards in the drawer. It is time to use them.
$ brew install picotool $ picotool version picotool v1.1.2 (Darwin 23.0.0, AppleClang-15.0.0.15000040, Release) this is the easiest way to install it. Of course if you like you can build it on your own. Here is the repo of picotool.
Below is the details of installing picotool.
==&amp;gt; Auto-updated Homebrew! Updated 3 taps (homebrew/bundle, homebrew/core and homebrew/cask).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the danger of wisdom</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240728/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 18:18:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240728/</guid>
      <description>The danger of wisdom Jack Gilbert (1925-2012) We learn to live without passion. To be reasonable. We go hungry amid the giant granaries this world is. We store up plenty for when we are old and mild. It is our strength that deprives us. Like Keats listening to the doctor who said the best thing for tuberculosis was to eat only one slice of bread and a fragment of fish each day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Telescope: a poem by Lousie Glück</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240724/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 18:37:14 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240724/</guid>
      <description>Telescope Telescope Louise Glück There is a moment after you move your eye away when you forget where you are because you’ve been living, it seems, somewhere else, in the silence of the night sky. You’ve stopped being here in the world. You’re in a different place, a place where human life has no meaning. You’re not a creature in body. You exist as the stars exist, participating in their stillness, their immensity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>useless beauty</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240720/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 13:25:59 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240720/</guid>
      <description>“nothing is really beautiful unless it is useless; everything useful is ugly for it expresses a need” ― Oscar Wilde, The Picture of Dorian Gray
“The truth is rarely pure and never simple.” ― Oscar Wilde, The Importance of Being Earnest
Kokoro is a 1914 Japanese novel by Natsume Soseki(夏目 漱石). It is the final part of a triology starting with To the Spring Equinox and Beyong (1912) and followed by The Wayfarer (1912).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>what we are</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240718/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 09:48:49 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240718/</guid>
      <description>What We Are What we are? We say we want to become what we are or what we have an intent to be. We read the possibilities, or try. We get to some. We think we know how to read. We recognize a word, here and there, a syllable: male, it says perhaps, or female, talent - look what you could do - or love, it says, love is what we mean.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the power of words, and narratives</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240708/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 10:50:21 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240708/</guid>
      <description>Again and again Bachmann shows how “the flawed language that has been passed onto us” can lead us to question what we know to be real, our own suffering selves included, and she asks what it means to grapple with these antinomies of world and word as public and political matters, not just private ones—indeed what it means to be a writer at all. “If we had the word, if we had language, we would not need weapons,” she said in a 1959 lecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>usa and haiku</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240628/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 13:37:12 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240628/</guid>
      <description>USA Last night two old men debated to show their incompetence. Too old and too bad.
Today, &amp;ldquo;The Supreme Court on Friday reduced the authority of executive agencies, sweeping aside a longstanding legal precedent that required courts to defer to the expertise of federal administrators in carrying out laws passed by Congress.&amp;rdquo; And, &amp;ldquo;Conservatives have now completed their generational goals of overturning Abortion, Affirmative Action, and Chevron. If y&amp;rsquo;all don&amp;rsquo;t think Obergefell and gay marriage is next on the chopping block, you must read &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>not reading</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240621/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 11:17:42 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240621/</guid>
      <description>not reading The art of not reading is a very important one. It consists in not taking an interest in whatever may be engaging the attention of the general public at any particular time. When some political or ecclesiastical pamphlet, or novel, or poem is making a great commotion, you should remember that he who writes for fools always finds a large public. A precondition for reading good books is not reading bad ones: for life is short.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>your brain is not a computer</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240614/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 10:44:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240614/</guid>
      <description>The empty brain, Aeon Robert Epstein
Senses, reflexes and learning mechanisms – this is what we start with, and it is quite a lot, when you think about it. If we lacked any of these capabilities at birth, we would probably have trouble surviving.
computers really do operate on symbolic representations of the world. They really store and retrieve. They really process. They really have physical memories. They really are guided in everything they do, without exception, by algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>use OCR on a mac</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240530/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 09:05:34 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240530/</guid>
      <description>Come across a blog on how to use OCR on a mac. The steps are as follows.
open the shortcuts app in the Applications folder click + button to create a new shortcut in the right sidebar, search for &amp;ldquo;extract text&amp;rdquo; drag &amp;ldquo;Extract Text from Image&amp;rdquo; in the list of possible actions from the right side bar into the main area on the left in the &amp;ldquo;Extract Text from Image&amp;rdquo; action, click on the pale &amp;ldquo;Image&amp;rdquo; and pick &amp;ldquo;Shortcut Input&amp;rdquo;, there is a &amp;ldquo;Receive Any Input from Nowhere&amp;rdquo; action appearing above the &amp;ldquo;Extract text from Image&amp;rdquo; back to the right sidebar, search for &amp;ldquo;copy&amp;rdquo; and drag &amp;ldquo;Copy to Clipboard&amp;rdquo; action right below the &amp;ldquo;Extract Text from Image&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>what next?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240510/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 15:15:46 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240510/</guid>
      <description>Finally have some time to think about the past weeks.
Michel Foucault: I don’t feel that it is necessary to know exactly what I am. The main interest in life and work is to become someone else that you were not in the beginning. If you knew when you began a book what you would say at the end, do you think that you would have the courage to write it?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes on 20240412</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240412/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 06:50:06 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240412/</guid>
      <description>Each of us has a window, that is ourselves. If we sample fast enough according to Nyquist-Shannon&amp;rsquo;s sampling theorem, we may reconstruct the world viewed through this window. Most of time, our views are just partial and approximate. It&amp;rsquo;s not so even because we are not fast enough and long enough.
It&amp;#39;s in vain to recall the past, unless it works some influence upon the present. -- Charles Dickens. David Copperfield There is nothing in the world so irresistibly contagious as laughter and good humor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fundamental belief and Bias</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240406/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 12:18:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240406/</guid>
      <description>每个人的生命都是通向自我的征途，是对一条道路的尝试，是一条小径的悄然召唤。觉醒的人只有一项义务：找到自我，固守自我，沿着自己的路向前走，不管它通向哪里。&amp;ndash; 黑塞
I can explain it only by a weakness of the scholarly mind that I have often observed in myself. I call it theory-induced blindness: once you have accepted a theory and used it as a tool in your thinking, it is extraordinarily difficult to notice its flaws. -- Daniel Kahneman (1934-2024) Steve Stewart-Williams: Psychologists have posited hundreds of cognitive biases over the years. A fascinating recent paper argues that they all boil down to one of a handful of fundamental beliefs coupled with confirmation bias.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bertolt Brecht</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240405/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 10:13:21 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240405/</guid>
      <description>German
Die das Fleisch wegnehmen vom Tisch Lehren Zufriedenheit. Die, für die die Gabe bestimmt ist Verlangen Opfermut. Die Sattgefressenen sprechen zu den Hungernden Von den grossen Zeiten, die kommen werden. Die das Reich in den Abgrund führen Nennen das Regieren zu schwer Für den einfachen Mann. English Translation:
Those Who Take the Meat from the Table Teach Contentment. Those for whom the taxes are destined Demand sacrifice. Those who eat their fill speak to the hungry Of wonderful times to come.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Daniel Kahneman</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240327/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 13:26:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240327/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>But you need to breathe. And you need to be.</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240322/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 10:55:13 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240322/</guid>
      <description>Albert Camus, Notebooks 1951-1959
Find meaning. Distinguish melancholy from sadness. Go out for a walk. It doesn’t have to be a romantic walk in the park, spring at its most spectacular moment, flowers and smells and outstanding poetical imagery smoothly transferring you into another world. It doesn’t have to be a walk during which you’ll have multiple life epiphanies and discover meanings no other brain ever managed to encounter. Do not be afraid of spending quality time by yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes on 20240321</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240321/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 15:34:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240321/</guid>
      <description>The world I live in Mary Oliver I have refused to live locked in the orderly house of reasons and proofs. The world I live in and believe in is wider than that. And anyway, what’s wrong with Maybe? You wouldn’t believe what once or twice I have seen. I’ll just tell you this: only if there are angels in your head will you ever, possibly, see one. A book must be an ice axe to break the sea frozen inside us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20240310</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240310/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 16:09:47 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240310/</guid>
      <description>“Everything that needs to be said has already been said. But since no one was listening, everything must be said again.” &amp;ndash; André Gide
“It was one of those March days when the sun shines hot and the wind blows cold: when it is summer in the light, and winter in the shade.” &amp;ndash; Charles Dickens, Great Expectations</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adam Wolff on debugging FB-Chat</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240228/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 10:19:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240228/</guid>
      <description>Today Adam Wolff tweeted a story about deugging FB-Chat. He is a technical fellow at Electric Capital. Below is it.
Before the major effort to redo the UI, FB Chat was super broken and we had no idea why.
We didn’t know what was wrong, but we knew the code was a mess. We set about rewriting both the front-end and the back-end in an effort to fix it.
The front-end rewrite pulled in a whole team of amazing engineers and became one of the big threads that led to reactjs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>explore/exploit tradeoff: model vs. reality</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240227/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 06:49:05 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240227/</guid>
      <description>To navigate life we create mental models of the world out there, and then we confuse the models for reality.
What is the explore/exploit tradeoff? The gambler needs to learn new knowledge about the machines and simultaneously use what they have already learned to optimize their decisions. In the literature, these two activities are referred to as exploring and exploiting. You can’t do both things at the same time. When you explore, you are pulling new arms on the bandit trying to figure out their expected payout.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20240226</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240226/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 07:29:52 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240226/</guid>
      <description>Aaron and Gaza Last Sunday, Airman Aaron Bushnell set himself on fire by Israeli Embassy in D.C. to protest US involvement in Gaza genocide. He died later after being transported to a local hospital on Sunday afternoon. What are we doing to stop the Gaza war?
&amp;ldquo;My name is Aaron Bushnell, I am an active-duty member of the United States Air Force and I will no longer be complicit in genocide,&amp;rdquo; he says in a video of the incident.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes on SICP</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240224/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 13:00:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240224/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; three foci of phenomena: the human mind, collections of computer programs, and the computer. Every computer program is a model, hatched in the mind, of a real or mental process. These processes, arising from human experience and thought, are huge in number, intricate in detail, and at any time only partially understood. They are modeled to our permanent satisfaction rarely by our computer programs. Thus even though our programs are carefully handcrafted discrete collections of symbols, mosaics of interlocking functions, they continually evolve: we change them as our perception of the model deepens, enlarges, generalizes until the model ultimately attains a metastable place within still another model with which we struggle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20240222</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240222/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 14:07:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240222/</guid>
      <description>子曰：“笃信好学，守死善道。危邦不入，乱邦不居。天下有道则见，无道则隐。邦有道，贫且贱焉，耻也；邦无道，富且贵焉，耻也。”
半轮秋月挂山崖，孤鸟悲鸣为有家。一己哀愁随落叶，百年世事入残霞。2022.10.2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SICP</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240220/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 10:26:19 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240220/</guid>
      <description>What’s in your hands, I think and hope, is intelligence: the ability to see the machine as more than when you were first led up to it, that you can make it more. &amp;ndash; Alan J. Perlis (1922–1990)
book SICP</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20240219</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240219/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 10:40:25 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240219/</guid>
      <description>$ git clone https://github.com/quickjs-ng/quickjs $ cd quickjs $ make $ $./build/qjs tests/microbench.js TEST N TIME (ns) REF (ns) SCORE (%) empty_loop 500000 9.20 date_now 100000 37.00 prop_read 100000 7.28 prop_write 100000 5.73 prop_create 10000 69.25 prop_delete 50000 71.60 array_read 50000 8.62 array_write 20000 17.19 array_prop_create 100 26.30 array_length_decr 200 12.39 array_hole_length_decr 200 19.25 array_push 100 45.00 array_pop 100 66.40 typed_array_read 50000 8.36 typed_array_write 20000 17.20 global_read 200000 3.98 global_write 100000 9.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>some notes</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240218/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 19:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240218/</guid>
      <description>Come across two authors: William Dalrymple (1965-) and Michael Axworthy (1962-2019). Going to read their books about Iran and India. Dalrymple has a podcast, EmpirePodUK. It is super.
A good chunk of the depression we are feeling comes not just from watching fellow human being massacred with impunity but also the realisation that those who tasked with &amp;lsquo;representing&amp;rsquo; us only represent money &amp;amp; power, that the wishes of millions of us is of no consequence to them</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>testing images</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240215/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 13:26:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240215/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>some books</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240209/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 12:59:40 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240209/</guid>
      <description>Book: Crime and Punishment “Your worst sin is that you have destroyed and betrayed yourself for nothing.”
― Fyodor Dostoevsky, Crime and Punishment
Book: Welcome to the Hyunam-Dong Bookshop “&amp;lt;..&amp;gt; Reading makes you see with clearer eyes and understand the world better. When you do that , you become stronger - the feeling you associate with success. But at the same time with pain. Within the pages, there&amp;rsquo;s much suffering, beyond that we&amp;rsquo;ve gone through in our finite experience of life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>love</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240129/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 07:10:37 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240129/</guid>
      <description>For one human being to love another: that is perhaps the most difficult of all our tasks&amp;hellip; the work for which all other work is but preparation.&amp;quot;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zinaida Serebriakova</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240127/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 18:23:15 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240127/</guid>
      <description>Her story was told by her paintings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>George Carlin (1937-2008) quotes</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240123/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 20:11:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240123/</guid>
      <description>“Here&amp;rsquo;s all you have to know about men and women: women are crazy, men are stupid. And the main reason women are crazy is that men are stupid.”
“The reason I talk to myself is because I’m the only one whose answers I accept.”
“Have you ever noticed that anybody driving slower than you is an idiot, and anyone going faster than you is a maniac?”
“Fighting for peace is like screwing for virginity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hannah Arendt</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240122/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 15:03:22 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240122/</guid>
      <description>The alternative is no longer between good and evil, but between murder and murder. — Hannah Arendt, The Origins of Totalitarianism</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>what is fiction?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240121/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:19:42 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240121/</guid>
      <description>Fiction, like all art, is primarily an emotional endeavour, and it succeeds or fails on the basis of its emotional sense.
The past is a canon we are all entangled with. Whether we know it or not, our combined human history is the reference we all share, and it is emotionally complex beyond any corpus of texts imaginable. Of course structural powers and systemic forces matter, of course political systems and expediencies matter, but power is concentrated in individuals, and individuals have emotional histories.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I write</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240120/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 20:04:27 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240120/</guid>
      <description>I write entirely to find out what I’m thinking, what I’m looking at, what I see and what it means. What I want and what I fear. &amp;ndash; Joan Didion
Without history, we are always children of time. Also our memory is very tricky.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shoveling snow with buddha</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240106/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 14:18:24 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240106/</guid>
      <description>Shoveling Snow With Buddha Billy Collins
In the usual iconography of the temple or the local Wok you would never see him doing such a thing, tossing the dry snow over a mountain of his bare, round shoulder, his hair tied in a knot, a model of concentration.
Sitting is more his speed, if that is the word for what he does, or does not do.
Even the season is wrong for him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>happiness is an encounter</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240105/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 18:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240105/</guid>
      <description>“Happiness is not something to be pursued, it is something met, an encounter. Most encounters, however, have a sequel; this is their promise. The encounter with happiness has no sequel. All is there instantly. Happiness is what pierces grief.” ―- John Berger</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes at 4-year-end</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231230/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 10:21:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231230/</guid>
      <description>From the start of COVID-19 pandemic, there are a lot of things happened. Wars are still raging including both Ukraine and Gaza. BLM protests around the world happend after George Floyd was choked to death. During this period, many notable leftists turned right. It is like a deconstruction process. Then I start to read James Baldwin and Hannah Arendt like unlearning or deprogramming.
Just imagine that you had lived and grown in a different place or time, read different books, you might have different expereinces and beliefs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>snow: alice&#39;s adventures in wonderland</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231226/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 18:01:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231226/</guid>
      <description>I wonder if the snow loves the trees and fields, that it kisses them so gently? And then it covers them up snug, you know, with a white quilt; and perhaps it says, &amp;ldquo;Go to sleep, darlings, till the summer comes again.”
PS. another manga book: the ends of a dream</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the chances of factual truth surviving the onslaught of power are very slim</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231221/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 14:33:58 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231221/</guid>
      <description>How could Isreal army be so cruel to bomb Gaza so indiscriminately?
Factual truth is in great danger of disappearance. It is engaged in a battle with political power, and it is the vulnerability of factual truth that makes deception possible. But this isn’t new either. Factual truth has always been in danger. It is easily manipulated and subject to censorship and abuse. Arendt cautions that factual truth is in danger of “being maneuvered out of the world for a time, and possibly forever.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jean cocteau: the secrets of beauty</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231213/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:58:39 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231213/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I wonder if beauty like all other feelings is just chemical and unconscious. The thinking is a game of words where logic should be the rule, however not always. Here is one piece of evidence: &amp;ldquo;Beauty hates ideas. It is sufficient to itself. A work of art is beautiful just as a person is beautiful. The beauty I speak of provokes an erection in the soul. One cannot argue with an erection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>与永恒拔河</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231208/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 14:21:43 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231208/</guid>
      <description>输是最后总归要输的 连人带绳都跌过界去 于是游戏终止 ——又一场不公平的竞争 但对岸的力量一分神 也会失手，会踏过界来 一只半只留下 脚印的奇迹，愕然天机 惟暗里，绳索的另一头 紧而不断，久而愈强 究竟，是怎样一个对手 踉跄过界之前 谁也未见过 只风吹星光颤 不休剩我 与永恒拔河 1978.2 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What if money expired?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231206/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 18:52:05 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231206/</guid>
      <description>First, an interesting book is coming, The dream you ordered is sold out what if money expired? There is an interesting article on money. Below are some notes.
Bartering is inconvenient because it requires “double coincidence of wants.” This makes it highly inefficient too.
As it evolved, money became increasingly symbolic. Money is abstract. It’s a belief system, a language, a social contract. Money is trust. But the rules aren’t written in stone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>artistic pcb with Gingerbread</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231127/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 10:05:05 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231127/</guid>
      <description>There are several ways to add artistic touch to the PCB. One way is to use SVG2shenzhen to create the KiCAD modules. Another way is Boldport PCBmode. Both use Inkscape to create SVG. The former is a kind of plugin for Inkscape. The latter is a part of interactive process using Python and has nothing to do with KiCAD. Boldport and Inkscape forms its own process.
Recently I noticed an OSHPark blog that mentioned another blog by Anne Barela from AdaFruit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>a part of power: you and me</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231124/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 15:40:14 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231124/</guid>
      <description>Most of people will side with the power to survive, not the truth, not the beauty, not the kids because the society is structured with power. I have to say that there are definitely a few exceptions out there. They are the light in the darkness and the hope out of desperation.
On March 31, 2023 at online Bucha Summit, Secretary Blinken commented as follow: &amp;ldquo;One year ago today, when Ukrainian forces liberated Bucha, they discovered a massacre.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the unbearable lightness of being</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231121/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 09:35:55 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231121/</guid>
      <description>When Roger Ebert commented on the film of 1988 directed by Philip Kaufman, there are two things standing out. One is that &amp;ldquo;There is a lot of nudity in the film but no pornographic documentary quality; the camera does not linger, or move for the best view, or relish the spectacle of nudity. The result is some of the most poignant, almost sad, sex scenes I have ever seen - sensuous, yes, but bittersweet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the world and our mind</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231110/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 20:32:51 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231110/</guid>
      <description>marcel proust (1871-1922): We fall in love for a smile, a look, a shoulder. That is enough; then, in the long hours of hope or sorrow, we fabricate a person, we compose a character. And when later on we see much of the beloved person, we can no longer, whatever the cruel reality that confronts us, strip off that good character, that nature of a woman who loves us, from the person who bestows that glance, bares that shoulder, than we can when she has grown old eliminate her youthful face from a person whom we have known since her girlhood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>on the shortness of life</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231106/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 15:39:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231106/</guid>
      <description>It is not that we have so little time but that we lose so much. &amp;hellip; The life we receive is not short but we make it so; we are not ill provided but use what we have wastefully.
Life can only be understood backwards; but it must be lived forwards. &amp;ndash; Soren Kierkegaard
[Man] is a specific organism of a specific nature that requires specific actions to sustain his life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As nice as you are</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231029/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 14:32:55 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231029/</guid>
      <description>After reading the Rivonia 1964, you have to admire Mandela and how fortunate South Africa had Mandela at that time. Look at Gaza now. The terrorist attack by Hamas seemed such a desperate choice when there was no choice left. Will Israel stop its war against Hamas? Will both Israel and Palestine return to two-state solution?
When Russia invaded Ukraine, US stands with Ukraine. When Israel invaded Palestine, US stands with Israel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mandela and political violence</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231028/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 12:56:38 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231028/</guid>
      <description>Rivonia 1964 from Rachael Meager.
the speech from the dock in the Rivonia trial (1964) Long Walk to Freedom (1994) Why Mandela and his comrades decided to pursue sabotage and other forms of political voilence?
“I, and the others who started the organisation [Umkhonto], did so for two reasons. Firstly, we believed that as a result of Government policy, violence by the African people had become inevitable, and that unless responsible leadership was given to canalise and control the feelings of our people, there would be outbreaks of terrorism which would produce an intensity of bitterness and hostility between the various races of the country which is not produced even by war.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: an open-air prison</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 07:20:51 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231020/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been 15 days. On Oct 7, 2023, Hamas launched a terrorist attack against Israel. Then Israel began its retaliatory air strikes to Gaza and its war against Hamas. This war is complicated. Two things should be clear. Hamas&amp;rsquo;s attack to Israel is a terrorist one. Israel shut down water and electricity to Gaza, and bombed hospital and church. It is war crimes against civilians.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curiosa</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 13:30:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231017/</guid>
      <description>In the age of Internet, how could we individual stay current with the world? How to gather the facts in the fast-going conflict, and form our opinions? Only free speech could lead to the truth.
the movie, Curiosa.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>unity and others</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230921/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 13:06:23 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230921/</guid>
      <description>Unity claimed that 70% of the top 1000 mobile game developers chose it. Its new policy of installation fee attracts a lot of critism and anger, from indie developers in particular. However, the cause of this is due to the market changes:
the market of mobile game has its first decline after 7 years&amp;rsquo; expansion. the population of mobile game stops to increase. the growth hey-day of mobile game is over.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>meta-game</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230831/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 13:19:58 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230831/</guid>
      <description>There are several things coming together recently. It&amp;rsquo;s time to present them together.
The first thing is a tweet. Now it&amp;rsquo;s hard to retrieve it but the idea is below. &amp;ldquo;They’re like the “entrepreneurship” professor that never built a business. They’re experts in the meta-game &amp;ndash; they’re polished speakers, engaging writers, and thought-leading tweeters. The problem, though, is that they’re not judged by customers, the market, or nature, instead they’re judged by their peers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>time</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230825/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 11:20:52 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230825/</guid>
      <description>“Time flows in the same way for all human beings; every human being flows through time in a different way.” ― Yasunari Kawabata
“For clearly it is impossible to touch eternity with one hand and life with the other.” ― Yukio Mishima, The Temple of the Golden Pavilion</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>past, now, and future</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230819/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 11:04:53 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230819/</guid>
      <description>“Most people are prisoners, thinking only about the future or living in the past. They are not in the present, and the present is where everything begins.” &amp;ndash; Carlos Santana
“The past is never dead. It&amp;rsquo;s not even past.” &amp;ndash; William Faulkner, Requiem for a Nun
“Where belief is painful we are slow to believe.” &amp;ndash; Ovid “Habits change into character.” &amp;ndash; Ovid “Nothing is stronger than habit.” &amp;ndash; Ovid</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>read</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230818/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 16:02:45 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230818/</guid>
      <description>Proof you can do harder things 20 things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my 20 years as a software engineer Advice should go with its context.
I still don’t know very much
The hardest part of software is building the right thing
The best software engineers think like designers
The best code is no code, or code you don’t have to maintain
Software is a means to an end
Sometimes you have to stop sharpening the saw, and just start cutting shit</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>you can do harder things</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230817/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 15:57:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230817/</guid>
      <description>When a precocious yet nonconformist teenager asks why they need to learn calculus, what should you say?
You know they will never use it in adulthood, outside of certain career choices.
You could say, “It’ll help you get into college,” but then they’re left wondering why college cares if you know calculus. And once they’re in college, maybe you could say, “To get a good job,” but why would a potential hirer care how you did in multivariate calculus if your job doesn’t require any knowledge of calculus?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230816/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 20:34:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230816/</guid>
      <description>what is most diffcult is to love the world as it is, with all the evil and suffering in it. - Hannah Arendt
They who dream by day are cognizant of many things which escape those who dream only by night. - Edgar Allen Poe</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>private life</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230807/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 08:43:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230807/</guid>
      <description>From BLM, I heard of James Baldwin. From the pandemic, I learnt Hannah Arenht. Both are writers. Baldwin left America for France because of racism in America. Arenht left Germany for America because of Nazism. Here, another name, Sophie Scholl, popped up.
&amp;ldquo;The paradox of education is precisely this - that as one begins to become conscious one begins to examine the society in which he is being educated.&amp;rdquo; - James Baldwin</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>what is you?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230726/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 07:53:38 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230726/</guid>
      <description>There is going to have the first Dark ID (DID) design. The idea of DID dwelled in my mind for about two years. Now I can finally see its form. I am not sure how others receive it but it&amp;rsquo;s mine, unique to what I am.
This reminds me of one thing that Jorge Borges said in Spanish. &amp;ldquo;Sólo perduran en el tiempo las cosas Que no fueron del tiempo.&amp;rdquo; After translation, it is roughly as follows: Only things that were not of time endure in time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>human condition</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230725/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 08:29:52 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230725/</guid>
      <description>The Rolling Stones has a song, You can&amp;rsquo;t always get what you want. It simply tells us that no matter how much we yearn it we can&amp;rsquo;t always get it. The angst and the pain we have to go through, it is real. It shows us what we are not who we are. It should help us to puncture the illusion we have about who we are supposed to be. It should wake up the dreams we are in like Shakespeare said, &amp;ldquo;We are such stuff as dreams are made on; and our little life is rounded with a sleep.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>罗刹海市</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230724/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 18:32:05 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230724/</guid>
      <description>忽忽三年，红尘永隔；盈盈一水，青鸟难通，结想为梦，引领成劳。
异史氏曰：“花面逢迎，世情如鬼。嗜痂之癖，举世一辙。‘小惭小好，大惭大好’。若公然带须眉以游都市，其不骇而走者盖几希矣！彼陵阳痴子，将抱连城玉向何处哭也？呜呼！显荣富贵，当于蜃楼海市中求之耳！”</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>your way</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230723/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 16:05:06 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230723/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Why are you looking around for help? Do you believe that help will come from outside? What is to come is created in you and from you. Hence look into yourself. Do not compare, do not measure. No other way is like yours. All other ways deceive and tempt you. You must fulfill the way that is in you.”
— C.G. Jung</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes 2023-07-21</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230722/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 07:08:17 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230722/</guid>
      <description>We are such stuff as dreams are made on; and our little life is rounded with a sleep.
The fool doth think he is wise, but the wise man knows himself to be a fool.
So we beat on, boats against the current, borne back ceaselessly into the past.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>history, the rich, and Tim Jacob Wise</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230719/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 19:57:45 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230719/</guid>
      <description>Divided and conquered. It is not just in America, it is quite everywhere?! Imagine that the whiteness is created by the rich for the poor, in America. Then the Redness is created by the power for the powerless, in China.
Tim Wise Part 3 the history of whiteness</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The despair of Ukraine and others</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230629/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 13:43:19 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230629/</guid>
      <description>There is one commentary on politico.eu on Ukraine by Mariam Naiem.
On June 6, a catastrophic event unfolded in Ukraine as the dam in Nova Kakhovka was destroyed, another war crime by Russia. I&amp;rsquo;d like to highlight the following paragraph.
&amp;ldquo;To us (Ukrainians), it feels as though the world is anticipating yet another tragedy, as if we are simply characters in a dystopian series. Only when faced with a concoction of pandemics, floods, bombings, torture and rape can we receive help and support.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the similar feel</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230615/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 08:58:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230615/</guid>
      <description>美国作家Cormac McCarthy去世了，看到了一个推引用了他小说中的一段话：
“They spoke less and less between them until at last they were silent altogether as is often the way with travelers approaching the end of a journey.”
这让我想起辛弃疾的词：
少年不识愁滋味，爱上层楼。爱上层楼，为赋新词强说愁。 而今识尽愁滋味，欲说还休。欲说还休，却道天凉好个秋！
岁月带来了似曾相识的沧桑感。
McCarthy还有写火的段落，比如在Blood Meridian:
“The flames sawed in the wind and the embers paled and deepened and paled and deepened like the bloodbeat of some living thing eviscerate upon the ground before them and they watched the fire which does contain within it something of men themselves inasmuch as they are less without it and are divided from their origins and are exiles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We are living through the end of the useful internet</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230614/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 09:10:55 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230614/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;We are living through the end of the useful internet. The future is informed discussion behind closed doors, in Discords and private fora, with the public-facing web increasingly filled with detritus generated by LLMs, bearing only a stylistic resemblance to useful information. Finding unbiased and independent product reviews, expert tech support, and all manner of helpful advice will now resemble the process by which one now searches for illegal sports streams or pirated journal articles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some quotes from A River Runs Through It</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230610/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 13:24:17 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230610/</guid>
      <description>A river runs through it by Norman Maclean
Like many fly fishermen in western Montana where the summer days are almost Arctic in length, I often do not start fishing until the cool of the evening. Then in the Arctic half-light of the canyon, all existence fades to a being with my soul and memories and the sounds of the Big Blackfoot River and a four-count rhythm and the hope that a fish will rise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>想要健康，远离代糖</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230609/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 13:19:07 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230609/</guid>
      <description>Sugar substitutes are often labelled as sugarless, sugar free, no sugar added, or aritificial sweeten.
越甜的食物往往含有更多的游离糖，包括果糖、蔗糖、葡萄糖等。甜味不仅意味着食物含有更多热量，而且甜味还会刺激大部分人的食欲，让人多吃，以获取更多的热量。这在食物丰富的现代社会，逐渐成了一个健康问题，与热量摄入过多相关的疾病成为个人、家庭和社会的沉重负担。
假如你是糖尿病的高危人群，比如肥胖，不要指望通过代糖降低罹患糖尿病的风险，有的研究反而提示改用代糖体重增加更多；假如你不是高危人群，也不要试图用代糖来防病，那不仅无效，还有可能增加心血管病和中风的风险。想要健康，还是应该尽量吃不甜的食物、喝不甜的饮料， 比如白水。
进化决定了我们对甜味的钟爱。漫长的进化过程中，人类大脑逐步形成了对糖的依赖，糖可以激活大脑中与奖赏和食欲相关的区域，导致食欲的增强。即使食物或者饮品中加入的是代糖，大脑也会通过甜味将其与高热量食物联系起来，因为高糖食物通常也是高能量食物。摄入代糖后，大脑可能会期望获得更多的能量，从而增加食欲。
想要健康，远离代糖。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>transparency of politics and defend freedom by force if necessary</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230607/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 16:58:47 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230607/</guid>
      <description>There are two books to note.
Gimme some truth by Jon Wiener, 1999 Wiener had a legal battle with the US government for over two and a half decades. One thing is that Nixon attempted to have Lennon deported in the spring of 1972. FBI kept a file on Lennon.
The basic issue was that government officials everywhere like secrecy. By keeping the public from learning what they have done, they hope to avoid criticism, hinder the opposition, and maintain power over citizens and their elected representatives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>night vision and the illusion of love</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230526/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 19:36:38 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230526/</guid>
      <description>a song, night vision, by Suzanne Vega When the darkness takes you With her hand across your face Don&amp;#39;t give in too quickly Find the thing she&amp;#39;s erased a poem, a sunday drive, by Margaret Atwood Burial by fire is the last mercy: decay is reserved for the living. The desire to be loved is the last illusion: Give it up and you will be free. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>penelope fitzgerald</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230521/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 08:51:53 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230521/</guid>
      <description>penelope Her characters are people in a muddle, hopeless cases and outsiders whom she called exterminatees. She does not think that people get what they deserve in this world. Her style is plain, and subtle. She is evasive and reserved. She is inspired by Ruskin and William Morris.
&amp;ldquo;novels arise out of the shortcomings of history.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;they are all gone into the world of light.&amp;rdquo;
Cavafy I have gazed so much on beauty that my eyes overflow with it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>blind like in a dream</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230519/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 11:02:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230519/</guid>
      <description>In a song by Horslips, you can&amp;rsquo;t fool the beast, there are a few lines interesting.
Ah yes, they&amp;#39;re blind already. They&amp;#39;re blind to love, blind to pain, Blind to hope, blind to gain. Ah you can fool them alright But can you fool the beast? Love Poem by Robert Bly:
When we are in love, we love the grass And the barns, and the light poles And the small mainstreet abandoned all nights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230514/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 09:44:51 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230514/</guid>
      <description>Two mini-stories: water-bottle In a library. Put my water bottle on the foutain stand and went into the restroom. Upon returning, my water bottle was gone. While I have left it this way many many times, the water bottle always stays there without leaving. Where is it?
I went outside and saw a man leaving. Ran to him and saw my water bottle in his hand. &amp;ldquo;Excuse me, that water bottle is mine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>嫌贫爱富是人之本性还是社会构建？</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230504/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 10:43:23 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230504/</guid>
      <description>纽约地铁上黑人流浪汉被谋杀已经有几天了。不少媒体的报道着墨于无家可归，却对大庭广众之下的私刑谋杀轻描淡写，这是很奇怪的事。对弱势群体的同情，似乎被无缘由的（对黑人、贫穷和无家可归者的）害怕和厌恶所取代。
社会学家Matthew Desmond有本书，Poverty by America。在一个访谈中他说，“许多人从贫穷中谋利。”
在百老汇音乐剧Hadestown中有首歌Why We Build the Wall这样唱道：
Why do we build the wall? We build the wall to keep us free ... The enemy is poverty And the wall keeps out the enemy And we build the wall to keep us free That’s why we build the wall We build the wall to keep us free Because we have and they have not Because they want what we have got The enemy is poverty And the wall keeps out the enemy And we build the wall to keep us free That’s why we build the wall We build the wall to keep us free </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>汉语中的数字</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230503/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 13:24:57 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230503/</guid>
      <description>汉语中数字有三种表达，阿拉伯数字，简体和繁体。繁体的主要用处是在会计记账和书写支票以防涂改。
PinYin Hanzi Daxie ling 零 零 yī 一 壹 èr 二 贰 sān 三 叁 sì 四 肆 wǔ 五 伍 liù 六 陆 qī 七 柒 bā 八 捌 jiǔ 九 玖 shí 十 拾 bǎi 百 佰 qiān 千 仟 wàn 万 万 yì 亿 亿 zhao 兆 兆 一兆 = 一万亿
两千两百一十七万四千六百 = 2217,4600
2,225,250 = 二十二万五千二百五十
两百零五 = 205
二 vs. 两 二三四 (two, three, four)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>things to do</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230430/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 10:04:28 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230430/</guid>
      <description>And you never meet the people. You never shake their hands. You never hear their story or tell yours. But somehow, in the act of making something with a great deal of care and love, something’s transmitted there. And it’s a way of expressing to the rest of our species our deep appreciation. So we need to be true to who we are and remember what’s really important to us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>even if you don&#39;t cheat, life cheats you anyway</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230423/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 08:50:10 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230423/</guid>
      <description>The title is a line from Lynn in the 2017 Thai movie, Bad Genius. &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t you see &amp;ndash; even if you don&amp;rsquo;t cheat, life cheats you anyway.&amp;rdquo;
When I learn English, the literal meaning is easy to get but the subtle culture and personal feel is hard to grasp. This can come to the difference between two persons. What do I know what you say means the same as I say the same words and sentences?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>唯心与唯物</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230420/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 20:57:33 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230420/</guid>
      <description>哲学的重要性在于世界观和价值观是与政治直接挂钩的。人类的种种冲突多半源于这两观的差异，以唯心为基础的哲学本质就是个人自我中心，而唯物论的基础则在于事实和科学认知。唯心论者从一己观世界，却不能跳出自己的局限与狭隘。虽是人性，却不利于解决人与人之间的矛盾。唯物论者看到宇宙浩渺，个人若尘，因此不必过于看重自己，或许对冲突的解决有利。
上篇提到佩索阿的诗句Nature is parts without a whole.其实可以稍稍改动一下： Truth is parts without a whole. Universe is parts without a center.这样看世界，或许更接近真相。当然，每个人从自己的经历得出的认识总是各有不同，知道生命的局限或许能看得更清楚更真实。
执与不执，总是一个问题。不过这个问题归根结底是如何选择，欲海无边，人生苦短。正如赫尔曼黑塞（Hermann Hesse）这样说：人们必须找到自己的梦，这样一来，这条路就会变得轻松许多。不过，没有一个梦可以永远持续，每个梦都会被新的梦取代，我们不可以想要紧抓任何一个梦。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nature is parts without a whole</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230417/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 09:56:01 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230417/</guid>
      <description>Nature, is parts without a whole. When I read this line, it is like a lightning strike. For each of us, there are some universial patterns of our experiece in this world. However, it is each of us that makes the whole, loosely connected and remotely located. Yes, there is no such a whole. No one could experience everything in this universe.
2023-04-20 Another line from Marilyn Monroe&amp;rsquo;s poem runs in the same vein.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>different forms of power?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230416/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 10:15:29 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230416/</guid>
      <description>In my backyard, there are always bird dramas going on and on. As you may know that birds are territorial animals. One year, a robin couple fought with another couple of black crow because somehow the black crow stole their chick and ate it. the poor robins called all their friends and had a fight on the garage&amp;rsquo;s roof. This spring, two Magpies built their nest on the apple tree. The construction took about a month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>antonio porchia</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230415/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 11:03:15 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230415/</guid>
      <description>I know what I have given you. I do not know what you have received.
Infancy is what is eternal, and the rest, all the rest, is brevity, extreme brevity.
Out of a hundred years a few minutes were made that stayed with me, not a hundred years.
One lives in the hope of becoming a memory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Reflection</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230401/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 12:16:30 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230401/</guid>
      <description>The quest for truth seems a noble endeavor. Generally I want to know more about the world and how it works. Why people do something instead of others? How to live your life to its best potentials? At the same time, I know I will have a short life, limited time, limited resources, and there is no way for me to know the world. At most, I am just experiencing my little world, family, a few friends, and a few colleagues.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>virginia woolf</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230330/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 10:10:29 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230330/</guid>
      <description>The flower bloomed and faded. The sun rose and sank. The lover loved and went. And what the poets said in rhyme, the young translated into practice. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eric Fromm</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230322/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 18:23:21 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230322/</guid>
      <description>Optimism is an alienated form of faith, pessimism an alienated form of despair.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>art, youth, and desire</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230320/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 11:01:42 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230320/</guid>
      <description>Here is one piece on Cormac McCarthy&amp;rsquo;s two books, The Passenger and Stella Maris, by Nicolas Medina Mora on Nation (Apr 3/10, 2023).
Ned Rorem jokes that everything in the world from music to food to people was either German or French. In the same facetious spirit, the author says every era in the history of taste can be classified into one of two categories: those that prefer the Opera Prima and those that prefer the Late Masterpiece.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>执象而求</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230313/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 10:24:33 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230313/</guid>
      <description>“When someone seeks,&amp;quot; said Siddhartha, &amp;ldquo;then it easily happens that his eyes see only the thing that he seeks, and he is able to find nothing, to take in nothing because he always thinks only about the thing he is seeking, because he has one goal, because he is obsessed with his goal. Seeking means: having a goal. But finding means: being free, being open, having no goal.”
君子之交，其淡如水。执象而求，咫尺千里。问余何适，廓儿忘言。华枝春满，天心月圆。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230227/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 10:27:17 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230227/</guid>
      <description>我已堕入无边的黑暗 只靠自生的光亮四处摸索</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes-02-23</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230223/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 08:59:48 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230223/</guid>
      <description>Call me Chihiro I watched a show, Call me chihiro. This reminds me of the opening sentence of Moby Dick, Call me Ishmael. I like it.
Chihiro&amp;rsquo;s ex-boss opened a shop of tropical fish. Chihiro thought he&amp;rsquo;s kind of her father. When I was in Singapore, somehow I&amp;rsquo;d like to visit Spain, Mexico or Argentina. I love that kind of passionate songs, dances, lives and spanish language. There is some happiness deep down there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pcb aluminium</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230210/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 09:46:20 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230210/</guid>
      <description>This Vlak1 lamp is a beauty.
Books, which we mistake for consolation, only add depth to our sorrow. -― Orhan Pamuk, My Name Is Red
How much can we ever know about the love and pain in another heart? How much can we hope to understand those who have suffered deeper anguish, greater deprivation, and more crushing disappointments than we ourselves have known? ―- Orhan Pamuk, Snow
Real museums are places where Time is transformed into Space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>walter benjamin</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230205/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 18:38:05 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230205/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;In modernist art, obscurity can be a conscious strategy. It is one of the ways in which the artwork can avoid being consumed too easily. Poems need to thicken their textures and scramble their syntax if they are not to slip down too easily, which is the fate of the commodity. Everyday language is no longer a medium of truth. It has grown stale and threadbare, and only by wreaking violence on it can you force it to yield something of value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>some quotes from Alex Rosenberg</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230203/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 13:40:40 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230203/</guid>
      <description>Here are some quotes from Alex Rosenberg.
Is there a God? No.
What is the nature of reality? What physics says it is.
What is the purpose of the universe? There is none.
What is the meaning of life? Ditto.
Why am I here? Just dumb luck.
Does prayer work? Of course not.
Is there a soul? Is it immortal? Are you kidding?
Is there free will? Not a chance!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes collected</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230126/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 09:34:03 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230126/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not true that fate slips silently into our lives. It steps in through the door that we have opened, and we invite it to enter. No one is strong enough or cunning enough to avert by word or deed the misfortune that is rooted in the iron laws of his character and his life.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ndash; Sandor Marai, Embers
“The words we read and words we write never say exactly what we mean.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>codes of interest</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230125/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 09:51:23 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230125/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you just want to hear these flipping sound. Here is the code for both Flip 7-segment digits and FlipDot.
FlipDigits FlipDots Another interesting thing is LED display of tixy.land.
Rust FFI and cbindgen: integrating embedded rust code in C.
Distinguishing an interpreter from a compiler, Jan 26, 2023. This leads to the excellent course, UCB CS294-113: Virtual machine and managed runtimes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220121/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 13:30:48 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220121/</guid>
      <description>Patrick Yang is a technical director at WCH. 南京沁恒 Here are some links. openwch github RISC-V based microcontrollers. CH32V003 32bit 48MHz 16KB flash, it is less than $0.5 for example. Arduino-wch58x. Another CH32V project.
Flipping dots
Kicad panelizing tool KiKit.
This 3D printing uses UTR-8100 transparent amterial, from PCBWay.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The secrets</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230120/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 16:31:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230120/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The Oprah-approved bestseller with three simple tenets: Science is fake, attitude causes everything and poor people don&amp;rsquo;t want to be rich.&amp;rdquo;
Read this thread.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes collected</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230119/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 15:20:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230119/</guid>
      <description>Nils Gilman pinned one tweet: People say adversity reveals character, but I say if you really want to know a man, give hime power.
Rosa Luxemburg: &amp;ldquo;In effect, every legal constitution is the product of a revolution.&amp;rdquo;
Every legal constitution is the product of a revolution. In the history of classes, revolution is the act of political creation, while legislation is the political expression of the life of a society that has already come into being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>news and readings</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230105/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 10:58:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230105/</guid>
      <description>The new US congress is still voting for its next speaker. From former speaker John Boehner, &amp;ldquo;What they&amp;rsquo;re really interested in is chaos. &amp;hellip;They want to throw sand in the gears of the hated federal government until it fails and they&amp;rsquo;ve finally proved that it&amp;rsquo;s beyond saving. Every time they vote down a bill, they get another invitation to go on Fox News or talk radio. It&amp;rsquo;s a narcissistic &amp;ndash; and dangerous &amp;ndash; feedback loop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20230104</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230104/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 10:28:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230104/</guid>
      <description>Start to read the condensed biography of Dostoevsky by Joseph Frank. This is to understand Dostoevsky&amp;rsquo;s works correctly with its political context of 19th century Russia. To read Dostoevsky, you have to understand the context.
Two nice tweets from Steve Stewart-Williams. One is the brain. The other Physics is weird.
Another thing is geometry in p5js in this github repo. Beautiful geometric shapes generated by code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>a few writers</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230102/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 11:24:26 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230102/</guid>
      <description>There are a few writers I love. Betrand Russell is one of them.
&amp;ldquo;The idea that the poor should have leisure has always been shocking to the rich. In the early nineteenth century, fifteen hours was the ordinary day&amp;rsquo;s work for a man; children sometimes did as much, and very commonly did twelve hours a day. When meddlesome busybodies suggested that perhaps these hours were rather long, they were told that work kept adults from drink and children from mischief.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>random notes</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221211/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 13:55:16 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221211/</guid>
      <description>Perception illusions Perceptual illusions show us in a clear and unambiguous way that we don&amp;rsquo;t directly perceive the world around us. Perceptual experience is a simulation—a mental model—that doesn&amp;rsquo;t always correspond to the reality it aims to depict.
human centered Whereas all the other animals have their heads low, eyes fixed upon the ground, the gods desired to give to man a sublime face, a face that could raise its eyes to the heavens above, contemplating the very stars in the sky.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Interesting Bits</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221205/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 06:14:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221205/</guid>
      <description>I whispered in his ear “I love you” he said delighted: “repeat it in my other ear so I regain my balance…”
If I had more time I would written a shorter letter. &amp;ndash; Cicero
I always feel that a man and a woman who do not like the same films will eventually divorce. &amp;ndash; Jean-luc Godard</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>weekly notes</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221126/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 20:09:14 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221126/</guid>
      <description>Green Koan by Rita Dove That the mind can go wherever it wishes is a kindness we&amp;rsquo;ve come to rely on; that it returns unbidden to the soul it could not banish and learns to thrive there is life&amp;rsquo;s stubborn mercy &amp;ndash; given to soften or harden us, as we choose.
Code is the biggest lever humanity has ever invented From Amjad Masad:
Code is the biggest lever humanity has ever invented.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Pointers</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221118/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 13:49:06 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221118/</guid>
      <description>One chinese book on Math and Programming Both math and programming are useful for data science and machine learning. This is the future of digital world.
Unique 2-in-1 calculator app in swift Twin-Calc is available for iPhone and iPad.
Vocaloid 6 This is a tool powered by AI tech from Yamaha. It can sing according to music and lyrics. Very powerful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>two types of writers</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221108/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 13:11:22 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221108/</guid>
      <description>“I think there are two types of writers, the architects and the gardeners. The architects plan everything ahead of time, like an architect building a house. They know how many rooms are going to be in the house, what kind of roof they&amp;rsquo;re going to have, where the wires are going to run, what kind of plumbing there&amp;rsquo;s going to be. They have the whole thing designed and blueprinted out before they even nail the first board up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the power of words and stories</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221107/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 13:36:35 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221107/</guid>
      <description>It is easy to forget how mysterious and mighty stories are. They do their work in silence, invisibly. They work with all the internal meterials of your mind and self. They become part of you while changing you. Beware the stories you read or tell; subtly, at night, beneath the waters of consciousness, they are altering your world.
&amp;ndash; Ben Okri
Ben Okri was born in 1959. In 1991, he won the Booker Prize with his novel The Famished Road.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mayakovsky</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221105/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 12:25:39 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221105/</guid>
      <description>Mayakovsky BY FRANK O&amp;#39;HARA 1 My heart’s aflutter! I am standing in the bath tub crying. Mother, mother who am I? If he will just come back once and kiss me on the face his coarse hair brush my temple, it’s throbbing! then I can put on my clothes I guess, and walk the streets. 2 I love you. I love you, but I’m turning to my verses and my heart is closing like a fist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Poems</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221104/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 16:26:54 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221104/</guid>
      <description>Piano by Edgar Kunz I held him together as long as I could, she says.
He stopped working, stopped coming upstairs.
He was like tissue paper coming apart in water.
Like smoke in my hands. It had nothing to do
with you, baby. You left when you had to.
I met a woman once who worked on pianos.
Said it was a hard job. The tools, the leverage.
The required ear.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nordic nRF5340</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221027/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 15:07:19 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221027/</guid>
      <description>use the Toolchain Manager inside nRF Connect for Desktop to automatically install toolchains. After that use the command line to build a project. Current version is v2.1.1.
$ cd /opt/nordic $ cd ncs/v2.1.1/nrf/applications/nrf5340_audio $ west build -b nrf5340_audio_dk_nrf5340_cpuapp --pristine -- -DCONFIG_AUDIO_DEV=1 -DCONF_FILE=prj_release.conf </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mike Davis</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 22:04:55 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221025/</guid>
      <description>For someone my age who was in the civil rights movement, and in other struggles of the 1960s, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen miracles happen. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen ordinary people do the most heroic things. When you&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of knowing so many great fighters and resisters, you can&amp;rsquo;t lay down the sword, even if things seem objectively hopeless.
I’ve always been influenced by the poems Brecht wrote in the late 30s, during the Second World War, after everything had been incinerated, all the dreams and values of an entire generation destroyed, and Brecht said, well, it’s a new dark ages … how do people resist in the dark ages?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>smoke, twitter, Democrats</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:50:01 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221018/</guid>
      <description>Brittney Cooper posted a question: is it a capitulation to the status quo by making any concessions to Democrats? All comes to the point that we vote in ways to reduce harm. that vote does not means a complete and total yes.
Adam Davidson has something about similarity between smoke and tweet. Go read it. The gist is that big corporations figured out how to abuse our instincts. It may be tweets, smoke, sugar, fat, salts, or others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hope is what life is</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 13:57:06 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221017/</guid>
      <description>In the dark time, to act is more important than to hope. Samantha Rose Hill once wrote that &amp;ldquo;for Hannah Arendt, hope is a dangerous barrier to courageous action. In dark times, the miracle that saves the world is to act.&amp;rdquo;
Life is always about hope. Then in an interview, Saidiya Hartman said the follows about the advice of &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t despair.&amp;rdquo; Here is the excerpt: &amp;ldquo;What is joy? What is joy?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>esp32 sdcard</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 18:46:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221016/</guid>
      <description>Here is SD example code from esp-idf. Here is one header file for esp32 fatfs.
use 4-line SD mode, consider the 10K pullup resistors on data lines code page: FF_CODE_PAGE : CONFIG_FATFS_CODEPAGE 437 US What is the biggest micro SD card for esp32 fatfs? 16GB?
FAT = file allocation table
FAT32 individual files on a FAT32 drive cannot exceed 4GB size limit. FAT32 partition must be less than 8TB.
exFAT file system: extended file allocation table.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20221015</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 19:00:48 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221015/</guid>
      <description>四通桥彭载舟抗议之后，孤勇者一时风行，据说上海封城的时候就流行过。当听到陈奕迅的演唱之后，总觉得耳熟。搜了搜，原来英雄联盟之双城之战的英文名Arcane，这部从游戏改编而来的漫画我其实是看过的。
致那黑夜中的嗚咽與怒吼 誰說站在光裡的才算英雄
由此又想到鲁迅的一首诗：
万家墨面没蒿莱，敢有歌吟动地哀。 心事浩茫连广宇，于无声处听惊雷。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading Pachiko</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 09:33:13 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221007/</guid>
      <description>Pachiko is not a story but a historical summary of Korean Japanese from 1910 to 1989. It reminds me of blacks in USA, Malays in Singapore, and all minority migrants in the Western countries.
Darwin&amp;rsquo;s natural selection is never about the fitness but the changes and the adaptation. Man will never change but be forced to change. That is the natural selection in human history. States, institutions like schools, police, courts, and many others are just ideas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>how to update to a new ESP-IDF release</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220925/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 09:20:04 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220925/</guid>
      <description>To run esp privilege separation, have to update esp-idf to v4.4.2.
This kernel-user application was announced several months ago. Just notice it today. It adds to another new option for WM.
$ cd $IDF_PATH $ git fetch $ git checkout v4.4.2 $ git submodule update --init --recursive $ ./install.sh $ . ./export.sh After the update, have to patch esp-idf for esp-privilege-separation.
$ cd $IDF_PATH $ git apply -v ../esp-privilege-separation/idf-patches/privilege-separation_support_v4.4.2.patch Then run the blink example inside esp-privilege-separation repo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>break through</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220917/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 12:38:38 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220917/</guid>
      <description>[2022-09-17] Finally got something wireless &amp;amp; audio working on esp32. This is just a start.
[2022-10-16] The proof of concept works seamlessly. Two parts, each works and both work together with no problem. Next step, hardware design and more bug fixes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loneliness</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220912/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 08:32:40 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220912/</guid>
      <description>An excerpt from Deleuze on Godard.
I can tell you how I think of Godard. He&amp;rsquo;s a man who works very hard, and it follows that he is completely alone. But this loneliness is not the common sort: it&amp;rsquo;s filled by a huge assortment of things. Not dreams, fantasies or projects, but actions, things and even people. It is a many-faceted, creative loneliness. It&amp;rsquo;s what lies behind Godard&amp;rsquo;s ability to operate powerfully on his own, but also as part of a team.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>interesting stuff</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220910/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 13:26:01 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220910/</guid>
      <description>For the first time someone complained that I swam too fast 记得以前看过一篇文章说游得好自然就快。我不知道自己游得好不好，反正并不快，所以一直在慢的泳道。大学时学会游泳，以前常游。后来有些时间没有条件，也没有时间。最近这段时间我已经坚持游了有近十年，快慢不论，体力还是有的。
120-year-old singing bird It&amp;rsquo;s amazing like a real bird chirp.
Horace Mann Die Gewohnheit ist ein Seil. Wir weben jeden Tag einen Faden, und schließlich können wir es nicht mehr zerreißen.
The habit is a rope. We weave a thread every day, and finally we can&amp;rsquo;t tear it apart anymore.
如果文化也如绳索，一丝一缕不断编织，到头来坚韧如枷锁难以断开。
Theodor W Adorno Kunst ist Magie, befreit von der Lüge, Wahrheit zu sein.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quine program</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220904/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 13:02:40 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220904/</guid>
      <description>Definition of Quine A quine program, or quine, is a program that outputs its own source code when runs without taking any input. It is called self-replicating program. Quines are possible in any Turing-complete programming language, as direct consequence of Kleene&amp;rsquo;s rescursion theorem.
Detour Quine&amp;rsquo;s paradox on self-reference.
&amp;#34;Yields falsehood when preceded by its quotation&amp;#34; yields falsehood when preceded by its quotation. Another paradox:
If the human brain were so simple that we could understand it, we would be so si mple that we couldn&amp;#39;t.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022-09-03 tetsuji</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220903/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 12:51:27 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220903/</guid>
      <description>news: too many books published According to the Penguin Random House/S&amp;amp;S antitrust trial it was revealed that out of 58,000 trade titles published per year, half of those titles sell fewer than one dozen books. 90 percent of titles sell fewer than 2,000 units.
video game music archive Garageband can play the mid file.
tetsuji Something interesting &amp;hellip;
reference bootNoodle 2020 janus: a polyglot binary for BGGP 2021 remote code execution on a Gameboy Colour Binary Golf Association BGGP 2021 github </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>认清形势放弃幻想并不容易</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220901/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 09:12:27 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220901/</guid>
      <description>book review Read a review on the last days of Sigmund Freud, its sideline goes like: danger surrounded Freud in Nazi-occupied Austria, why did it take him so long to see it? The book by Andrew Nagorski, Saving Freud: the rescuers who brough him to freedom, offered to tackle this question in 1938.
Whatever controversy brought by psychoanalysis, Freud knew the dark undercurrent of human behavior and he was critical of the false security offered by our wishful illusions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>science, value</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220830/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 09:05:28 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220830/</guid>
      <description>the value of science In 1955 Richard Feynman (1918-1988) had one essay, The Value of Science, published in Volume XIX of Engineering and Science.
My favorite quote from Feynman is as follows:
** Science is a way of trying not to fool yourself. The first principle is that you must not fool yourself, and you are the easiest person to fool. **
Carl Sagan in his book, The demon-haunted world, said something similar:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>语言和世界</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220826/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 10:21:37 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220826/</guid>
      <description>words and the world The true alchemists do not change lead into gold; they change the world into words. &amp;ndash; William Gass (1924-2017)
语言一如迷雾又如谜语，是一面镜子照见了当下，是一张照片抓住了某时某地某事。语言能够做到的不过是记录偌大世界一个人的一个瞬间，其他的一切不过是我们的想象而已。语言是虚构宇宙的一切。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>language</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220825/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 18:15:15 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220825/</guid>
      <description>编程与写作 写东西和编程序有些类似之处。当学习语言的时候，许多与之相关的知识也需要学。在没有自己的想法之前，写东西其实就是模仿他人的东西，练习再练习。
embrace despair the discrepancy between the world we live in and the world we might like to live in，the discrepancy between the world we live in and the world perceived in our mind
梦想与现实之间的差异（人类现状两个极端的差异） 感知与世界之间的差异（有限与无限之间）
the most difficult thing is to love the world with all the evil and suffering in it
人生如深渊，唯一的路途就是不断地坠落。而如果世界不止是春暖花开，还有凛冽寒冬，你还会热爱这个世界？
人哪有好坏，世界哪有黑白，而人生不过是自娱自乐，制造工具制造衣食，进而制造其他的一切，从随机和不确定中制造秩序、好坏、黑白、贫富和等级。
艺术 Art is the lie that enables us to realize the truth. &amp;ndash; Picasso</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why write?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220824/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 14:54:16 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220824/</guid>
      <description>如果能记下过去，未来就能有个可靠的参考，因为人的记忆实在是靠不住的。一个人会忘记，一个人会修改记忆，一个人还会添加记忆。这和一个社会会不断地修改历史、不断地重新解释历史、不断地创造历史其实是一回事。无论如何，也要让自己现在过得舒服点容易点。
不过语言自身也是一个不断更新的媒体，新的字词和概念不断添加进来，旧的字词不断获得新的意思。能在语言的波涛中留下来的，一定是个独立的世界，自给自足，浑然一体。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>人生苦短</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220821/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 09:02:36 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220821/</guid>
      <description>人生苦短不在于时间，而是快乐总是短暂。从错误推演正确，从无知而得经历，从短暂而知无常，短是个问题而时间不是。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hope and life</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220820/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 08:26:42 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220820/</guid>
      <description>Life The most tragic form of loss isn&amp;rsquo;t the loss of security; it&amp;rsquo;s the loss of the capacity to imagine that things could be different. -~ Ernst Bloch
Time Days to come stand in front of us like a row of lighted candles— golden, warm, and vivid candles.
Days gone by fall behind us, a gloomy line of snuffed-out candles; the nearest are smoking still, cold, melted, and bent.
&amp;ndash; C.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Folly&#39;s Antidote</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220818/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 17:59:27 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220818/</guid>
      <description>Folly&amp;rsquo;s Antidote But all historians are prisoners of their own experience. We bring to history the preconceptions of our personalities and of our age. We cannot seize on ultimate and absolute truths. So the historian is committed to a doomed enterprise &amp;ndash; the quest for an unattainable objectivity.
Conceptions of the past are far from stable. They are perennially revised by the urgencies of the present. When new urgencies arise in our own times and lives, the historian&amp;rsquo;s soptlight shifts, probing at last into the darkness, throwing into sharp relief things that were always there but that earlier historians had carelessly excised from the collective memory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>any luck?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220815/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 14:24:06 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220815/</guid>
      <description>Our culture is centered around success in almost any area - work, art, marriage and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s committed to resisting the idea that all of this involves way more luck and uncertainty than we&amp;rsquo;d like to admit.
For example, if you die climbing everyone says you are a foolhardy idiot. But if you just don&amp;rsquo;t die - and everyone who climbs long enough knows part of that is luck - everyone says you are a hero and an icon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>一梦有无中</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220814/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 12:21:54 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220814/</guid>
      <description>8月12日英国作家拉史迪在纽约的一个演讲上遇袭，随即他的小说《撒旦诗篇》冲上畅销书榜。他的书于1988年9月出版，在伊斯兰国家引发大论战，许多穆斯林指责该书亵渎了先知穆罕默德。次年2月伊朗精神领袖霍梅尼下了追杀令。拉史迪接受英国警方保护，躲躲藏藏多年。现在，悬赏追杀拉史迪的奖金已经高达3百万美元。
科学的进步并没有解决人类社会的诸多问题，宗教的受众依然颇多。就如弗洛伊德说的，宗教不过是大众的幻觉。许多人步调一致，在重塑现实的幻觉中，以为自己获得了幸福，获得了免于苦难的庇护。当然，分享这一切的人们自己并不会承认这仅是幻觉。
如果说《撒旦诗篇》挑战了许多人生而有之的身份认同，挑战了宗教信仰的正统，同时也挑战了国家和文化的正统。这些年来，民粹主义在全球沉渣泛起。而在这个多变的世界上，怎样才算是正统？当一个社会的包容空间不断缩小，当一个社会推崇通过暴力而非理性来解决问，文化和国家这样的认同是否也在步入宗教的后尘，成为大众的幻觉？
PS. The Satanic Verses incident is known as the Story of the Cranes in the Islamic tradition. It narrates the occasion when the Prophet Muhammad (died 632 CE) mistook the whispers of Satan for divine revelation. Of course, all Muslim group and sects today vehemently reject the Satanic Verses incident on both theological and historical grounds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reality</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220813/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 21:05:40 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220813/</guid>
      <description>Science shows us a reality of the universe, not complete but better than guessing. However some problems of human being are not scientific but social. Each of us has our own small world, so our own different realities. Our worlds are small and partial of the whole world. Some overlapping perhaps. But how much?
This reminds me of the story by Natalia Ginzburg, Family Lexicon. In this memoir, Natalia moved between fact and fiction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>stock market and war</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220812/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 08:27:34 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220812/</guid>
      <description>世界是很奇怪的。通货膨胀依旧，乌克兰抵抗俄罗斯的入侵依然，美国股市在技术性的经济衰退中一片繁荣景象。似乎乌克兰的战火只要还在乌克兰，世界就依然太平，似乎通胀只要没有影响到自己，经济就依旧繁荣。夏季的热浪从来没有如此普遍，只要没有吹进自己的家里，气候还依然正常。就像乌克兰不仅为自己的自由而战，而且为世界的和平而战一样。无数挣扎在贫困线的人们在为通胀和气候变暖付出代价，而其他人却丝毫不受影响。The war affects Ukraine. The inflation affects the poor. The climate change affects the vulnerable.
Here is Volodymyr Yermolenko&amp;rsquo;s orignial tweet. He is a Ukrainian philosopher and chief editor at Ukraine World.
War is when your friends die. When you see this breathless cruelty of death. You remember talks with this brave young man, a talented scientist, now he&amp;rsquo;s gone. Or a woman who cares about her rose garden, and you thought of her as the kindest person on earth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>避讳之怪</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220805/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 13:31:06 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220805/</guid>
      <description>前几天因为美国议长佩洛西访问台湾，社交媒体上热闹了一阵。在佩洛西离开台湾之后，中国立即开始在台湾附近海域进行实弹演习作为反制。为此，新华社发了公告(www.news.cn)，其中为了所谓的避讳，将军事“演习”改为军事“演训”。
避讳本来就是陈规陋习，在封建社会也只是不提君王、贵族或高官的名号以示尊重，名讳而已。不过在习近平准备终身连任的过程中，党章宪法都可以修改，避讳从名讳升级到了姓讳也就不奇怪。这无论怎样都是件很荒唐的事，难道以后别人都不能姓习了。习字从此只能习近平一人独享？
邓小平敢开放敢于打破终身制，其他不论，仅此一点就可以写进史书。而习近平却在搞复辟，修改宪法以便终身连任。而现在利用网络审核和过滤，大肆进行封建避讳。这种倒退是逆历史潮流，完全违背自由平等的普世价值。不过，复辟也只是一时热闹，迟早是要失败的。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>what a man-made recession!</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220726/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 09:24:07 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220726/</guid>
      <description>“And they laughed a little and were very friendly together, the three of them, Anna, Emanuele and Giustino; and they were pleased to be together, the three of them, thinking of all those who were dead, and of the long war and the sorrow and noise and confusion, and of the long, difficult life which they saw in front of them now, full of all the things they did not know how to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220725/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 10:32:11 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220725/</guid>
      <description>For a man who no longer has a homeland, writing becomes a place to live. &amp;ndash; Theodor Adorno
In our society there seems a general rule that the more obviously one&amp;rsquo;s work benefits others, the less one is likely get paid for. &amp;ndash; David Graeber</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>一如夏虫</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220724/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 10:32:11 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220724/</guid>
      <description>I wish you happiness, if there is such a thing, as happiness.
&amp;ndash; Natalia Ginzburg, Happiness, as Such
不知从什么时候开始，我已经不再追求幸福。一个人能够做点自己喜欢并力所能及的事情，看看周遭的世界，就够了。宇宙之大单是看看NASA发的照片就可感知一二。火星的表面一如地球上的荒漠，借由韦伯太空望远镜我们可以更清晰地看到更多星系，若干光年以前的景象。时间太少，心愿太多如书，看不过来，实现不及。而读书越来越像雾里看花，文字似乎可以给我一个世界，可是这个世界几分真实几分假？这个夏天超乎寻常地越来越热了。宇宙星空离我们越来越近，而家却离我们越来越远。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>plan</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220708/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 15:50:59 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220708/</guid>
      <description>What are we going to do with the projects? key: on the way to complete the design. proceed to prototype. wm: the concept interesting. finalize the details. start the design. read &amp;amp; code </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220704/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 08:29:31 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220704/</guid>
      <description>Here is a short note on Gillian Rose&amp;rsquo;s Love&amp;rsquo;s work from Merve Emre.
Love’s work is coextensive with the work of thinking and the work of criticism. Despite what advice columns and self-help books might teach, love, like criticism, is a peculiarly autocratic pursuit. One authorizes one’s own judgments and must live with the consequences. Sometimes—most of the time, some would say—we get it wrong. We err on the side of indulgence or cruelty, blind to (blinded by?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pessoa</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220703/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 08:42:53 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220703/</guid>
      <description>The book of disquiet is a great book, unique in its own way.
To write is to forget. Literature is the most agreeable way of ignoring life. Music soothes, the visual arts exhilarates, the performing arts (such as acting and dance) entertain. Literature, however, retreats from life by turning in into slumber. The other arts make no such retreat— some because they use visible and hence vital formulas, others because they live from human life itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to do about Roe v Wade after Supreme Court overturns</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220624/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 09:24:29 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220624/</guid>
      <description>Today the US Supreme Court overturns Roe v. Wade. This ended the right to abortion upheld for decades. From the leak in early May to this ruling near the end of June, there is time to prepare and to act. But still, what can we do next to codify the right to abortion?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build a real business to last on the top and others</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220623/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 14:39:01 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220623/</guid>
      <description>Just come across the tweets from Marcelino Pantoja. Feel something with the followings. One is that Steve Jobs on building a real company. The other is that Snowflake CEO Frank Slootman on competition.
The difficult thing to start a business is what to build, what is the feature of a product you really want but can&amp;rsquo;t find. But that&amp;rsquo;s not enough. How can you expand your product into a platform with that particular product.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>wild goose</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220618/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 13:52:08 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220618/</guid>
      <description>Wild goose made in PCB is inspired by the poem of Wild Geese by Mary Oliver.
The design uses strong contrast to show the changes and the unchanged. You are the same goose regardless of color.
黑白相对，前者为正片，而背面为负片。同学少年指相识于学校，那时意气风发，鸿鹄之志仍在。同时也是不识愁滋味的时候。天凉秋好化自辛弃疾的词，而今识尽愁滋味，欲说还休，欲说还休。却道天凉好个秋。
那么什么变了，什么没有变？人变思念不变。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Postcards</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220611/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 09:28:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220611/</guid>
      <description>Black Postcards I
The calendar all booked up, the future unknown. The cable silently hums some folk song but lacks a country. Snow falls in the grey sea. Shadows fight out on the dock.
II
Halfway through my life, death turns up and takes your pertinent measurements. We forget the visit. Life goes on. But someone is sewing the suit in the silence.
I hear my country in your voice From Romeo Oriogun:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>language and the world</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220610/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 10:22:54 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220610/</guid>
      <description>Life is nothing but a lightning between darkness. Without the words, we can feel the world. This world close to you and within your touch is vorld. To live is just experiencing the vorld. Each vorld is within the world, independent or dependent, with or without overlapping.
We see the vorld and feel the vorld. We long to know more about the world beyond our senses. We create tools like telescope, microscope, oscilloscope, electroscope to extend our sight.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Story of Epstein</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220603/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 14:19:14 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220603/</guid>
      <description>This is from Adam Davidson.
I spent two years working on the Jeffrey Epstein podcast, Broken. I became close with many of his victims and learned a lot of stuff that&amp;ndash;for annoying legal reasons&amp;ndash;we can&amp;rsquo;t publish.
That experience has fundamentally reshaped how I see the world.
TL;DR: I knew that rich and powerful men can get away with a lot. I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize just how much they can get away with and just how much the entire system&amp;ndash;courts, journalism, prosecutors&amp;ndash;works inadvertently and deliberately, to reinforce their impunity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gillian Rose</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220601/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 09:29:43 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220601/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I will stay in the fray, in the revel of ideas and risk; learning, failing, wooing, grieving, trusting, working, reposing &amp;ndash; in this sin of language and lips.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;We have to follow not the path of self-enlightening doubt, but the path of despair. &amp;hellip; This path is self-completing because it is more radical than mere doubt, and because it presents the &amp;lsquo;complete&amp;rsquo; forms of &amp;lsquo;untrue consciousness in its untruth&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;This is the counsel of despair which would keep the mind out of hell.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ramanujan problem</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220531/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 15:12:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220531/</guid>
      <description>Find the value of x and y for the following two equations:
$$ \sqrt{x} + y = 7 $$ $$ x + \sqrt{y} = 11 $$
My solutuin is based on a guess. From the above, the instinct is that both x and y are the numbers like 1, 4, 9, 16, etc. If we rewrite the equations as follows:
$$ x = (7 - y)^2 $$ $$ y = (11 -x)^2 $$</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>René Girard</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220529/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 13:42:51 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220529/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What opportunities can’t I see because they’re not prestigious enough?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t really outperform your peers with quality per se, you outperform your peers by finding underpriced quality that others don’t judge to be valuable.&amp;rdquo;
Girard&amp;rsquo;s philosophy teaches us that the world is filled with under-priced opportunities that are only available to people who are comfortable with promising, but low-status projects.
The modern world rejects imitation in favor of originality at all costs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What can we do about it?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220528/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 16:09:54 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220528/</guid>
      <description>Starting from 2020, the pandemic set the background for this decade and further. Then George Floyd and subsequent BLM opened the ugly side of America wide to the world. The only light note was that the new genetic vaccine was developed in a record speed and saved the world from the virus. With that, it is still tragic to see that the zero-policy in China was still effective causing unnecessary harms to people brutally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>如何改变</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220524/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 10:27:11 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220524/</guid>
      <description>每个人都有一个自己的世界。人人不同，每个人的世界也不同，这些小世界都是有局限的。我们的小世界存在于一个巨大的世界之中。生命不过是黑暗之间的一道闪电，如何改变自己，如何体验这个巨大的世界，是每个人都该问的问题。
逻辑需要训练，科学需要学习，人的认知偏差需要时时警惕。语言如迷雾一般，需要小心驾驭。而交流分享自己的小世界，是理解那个大世界的唯一办法。居里夫人说，生活不需担心，而要理解。明白越多，害怕就越少。
Nothing in life is to be feared, it is only to be understood. Now is the time to understand more, so that we may fear less. &amp;ndash; Marie Curie</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>liberty and freedom</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220525/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 09:21:20 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220525/</guid>
      <description>1 Yesterday 21 people were killed in an attack by a lone gunman at an elementary school in Uvalde, Texas. The 18-year-old gunman was killed by police. Why tragedies like this happen again and again in the United States? Buffalo, Laguna Woods, Sandy hook, Santa Fe High, El Paso, and so many others.
March 13, 1996. 26 years ago, a gunman entered Dunblane Primary School in Scotland, killed 16 kids and a teacher.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are the ever-changing you still yourself?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220520/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 09:42:06 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220520/</guid>
      <description>Kant has four big questions for philosophy.
What can I know? How should I act? For what can I hope? What is the human being? This writing has something to do with Kant&amp;rsquo;s last question.
In the book of &amp;ldquo;Last Chance to See&amp;rdquo;, Douglas Adams told an anecdote about the Golden Pavilion Temple in Kyoto.
&amp;ldquo;I remembered once, in Japan, having been to see the Gold Pavilion Temple in Kyoto and being mildly surprised at quite how well it had weathered the passage of time sicne it was first built in the fourteenth century.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>自然属性与道德</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220519/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 10:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220519/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Moral worth should be judged not in terms of the naturalness of a trait, but rather in terms of how that trait impacts the wellbeing of everyone affected by it. Thus, violence is natural but bad, medicine unnatural but good.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ndash; Steve Stewart-Williams, The Ape that Understood the Universe
道德与否不应该以某一属性是否自然为依据，而是应该以该属性是否会影响所有人的福祉为据。正因为如此，暴力是自然的却是不对的，医药是非自然的却是好的。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Population</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220518/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 10:27:15 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220518/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The battle to feed all of humanity is over.&amp;rdquo; This is the first line of Paul Ehrlich&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;lsquo;The Population Bomb&amp;rsquo;, published in 1968. The book sold millions of copies and was taken very seriously.
The Malthus&amp;rsquo;s prediction of what is now called Malthusian trap. That is more an observation of the cyclical patterns of population boom and bust that had happened for most of human existence. The the industrial revolution changed things at some great costs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why France and German behave so?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220516/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 18:17:54 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220516/</guid>
      <description>今天的法国总统马克龙和德国总理舒尔茨很像1938年二战之前的英国首相张伯伦和法国总理达拉第，慕尼黑协定将捷克的苏台德割让给德国并没有带来一厢情愿的和平，只是揭开了二战的序幕。
“尽管试着将这种方式称为谈判，但绥靖的味道却难也遮掩。1938年张伯伦和达拉第去慕尼黑见希特勒的教训依然适用：给独裁者想要的并不能阻止他要求更多；那只能让他相信你不够强大，以致不能阻挡他得到他想要的。否则，顺着独裁者的思路，你早在事情伊始之时就该站起来抵抗。“
国际象棋大师@Kasparov63 在2014年写了这本书《Winter is coming》，正是俄罗斯入侵乌克兰并强占克里米亚之后。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why read Arendt?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220513/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 21:32:16 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220513/</guid>
      <description>汉娜阿伦特是德国出生的美国政治哲学家。受幸运女神的眷恋，在海德堡大学师从雅士培、海德格尔，国会纵火案后迅速离开纳粹德国，又从法国的隔离营逃脱，后来得到赴美签证离开欧洲。1941年5月22日，当她到达美国时，口袋里只有25美元，不会英语（德语是其母语），35岁，而她的重要作品还没有一部问世。
最近看到了Samantha Rose Hill的一条推文，才重新捡起了汉娜阿伦特的书，一发不可收拾，因为这次看进去了，也似乎看明白了。试着写下来，stop-think，停下来想想，看看自己是不是真得想清楚了。
阿伦特对孤独有独到的见解，隔离不是真正的孤独，不去与他人交流，不去行动才是真正的孤独。
她对如何思考也很特别。她说，思考就是一个人和自己的对话，而思考的主题是什么呢？个人的经验。正是因为有了对世界的体验，我们才会有困惑才会发现问题，才会试着解决问题。而理解这个世界，是阿伦特的最爱。如果说阿伦特是哲学家，那么她的哲学与以往的哲学家颇有不同，她不愿属于任何一个理论框架。相反，她的哲学是基于个人体验，是从下到上，是接地气的，而不是形而上的虚无缥缈。如果你也想理解这个世界，不妨试着读下阿伦特。
阿伦特自己是难民，从离开德国之后就无国籍了十多年，直到后来加入美国籍。所以她对无根的漂泊感受特别深。她还专门写过一篇文章，题目就是《我们这些难民》。作为一个移民，从漂泊时的思念到定居后难以融入再到四海为家，人之所在心之所安，这样的过程会让你更加爱读阿伦特。
阿伦特有本书叫《黑暗时代的人们》，她那时的背景当然是二战。而现在新冠疫情还没有结束、俄罗斯入侵乌克兰的仗也似乎没有到头，世界各国在印钱之后面临高通胀面临衰退的压力，前些时候美国高院泄漏出来或许会推翻反禁止堕胎的判例更是让人担心，这或许是我们自己的黑暗时代。也正因为如此，阿伦特的书更值得一读，也让人更有共鸣。
我爱读阿伦特，她试着理解她的世界，顺着她的思路，她其实是指引你思考的方法。思考不是要达致一个结论，思考是个永不停止的过程。在忙碌的生活中，我们或许需要时不时停下脚步，问问自己是否走在自己想走的路上，问问自己这世界究竟有什么改变，想想如何努力地去爱自己去爱家人，去爱这个并不完美的世界。去读读阿伦特吧。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>批评老中医思维</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220507/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 18:42:20 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220507/</guid>
      <description>老中医思维就是想当然，不讲逻辑，不看证据，胡乱禁忌，抱残守缺。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>me and you</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220506/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 09:16:58 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220506/</guid>
      <description>At a night with stars, you and I, may see a similar sky. At a day with sunshine, you and I, may see a different city. I am not sure what your city is. My city is so small and it has three grocery stores, two clinics, one children hospital, four schools, one library, two gas stations, a few parks and a river. Three remote cities still in my memory. Plus a few colleagues and friends.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abortion right is women&#39;s right</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220503/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 13:17:12 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220503/</guid>
      <description>The leaked draft from the Court is a regression. Hope Amecian people will shoot it down.
Nobody has the right to use your body against your will, event to save your life, or the life of another person. That’s it. That’s the argument.
You cannot be forced to donate blood, or marrow, or organs, even though thousands die every year on waiting lists. They cannot even harvest your organs after your death without your explicit, written, pre-mortem permission.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vorld</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220501/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 19:48:27 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220501/</guid>
      <description>vorld Vorld is a personal world. V is just a half of W. In your time, the people you have met, the places you have been, the things you have done, these are your vorld. Just a small part of the world.
desire Lacan has a famous dictum, man’s desire is the desire of the Other. What you want, in the end, is a construct by the vorld from the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>旧作重读</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220425/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 10:39:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220425/</guid>
      <description>“人造之物皆有生命。”记不得是在哪里看到这段话，“语言自然而生，文化随之而来。建房修葺，修路搭桥，这些不都是生命的延展？学校教堂医院，警局政府法院，这些不都是生命的附属？“</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Derrida&#39;s Deconstruction</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220423/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 13:49:58 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220423/</guid>
      <description>Michael Peterson Is his writing difficult? I suppose so, in the sense that it uses a technical vocabulary specific to his work and the tradition he is working from. These are, most basically: phenomenology, semiotics, psychoanalysis, and Western philosophical history.
Combined, this leaves us in a position where the objects of his inquiry are varied and risk being construed as overly general. He writes about ethics, politics, language, time, space, forgiveness, the death penalty, sovereignty, Marxism, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>乌克兰和上海</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220422/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 16:24:39 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220422/</guid>
      <description>峰峦如聚，波涛如怒，山河表里潼关路。望西都，意踟蹰。 伤心秦汉经行处，宫阙万间都做了土。兴，百姓苦；亡，百姓苦。
在我们这儿新冠疫情早在三月就结束了。到现在新冠已经有六波了，不过因为有mRNA疫苗的保护（大多数人都接种了三针）一切也算是正常。口罩还有人戴，公共交通还要求戴，其它场所就是自愿的了。现在的新闻主要就是乌克兰和上海。
俄罗斯入侵乌克兰已经50多天了，国内有不少人竟然说，俄罗斯入侵乌克兰是因为北约东扩，并以此为俄罗斯的侵略战争辩护。如果二战时希特勒入侵波兰是侵略，当年美国进攻伊拉克是侵略，为什么普京入侵乌克兰就不是侵略？站在俄罗斯那些邻国的角度，为什么那些国家要或者想要加入北约？不就是担心俄罗斯的威胁。而这次俄罗斯的入侵更证明了这些担心并非空穴来风。再说了，俄罗斯为什么不想那些邻国加入北约？不就是担心人民自己选择的自由会威胁或动摇独裁专制。对乌克兰的真正支持只有一种，那就是提供各种支援，包括食物、药品和武器弹药，支持乌克兰保家卫国，直到最后的胜利。
上海这个两千五百万人口的大都市因为奥密克戎而封城，由此引发各种惨剧。许多人没有受到新冠影响，却承受了封城的苦难。有人在家挨饿，有人急症得不到救治，有人不堪重负跳楼自尽。大白和红马甲却享受了至高权力的威风，以防疫之名可以随意殴打、抓捕，擅闯民宅。美领馆撤了，日本领馆没吃的了，韩国领事致函复旦请求让韩国留学生回国。一个国际大都市为什么会变成这样？武汉封城，西安封城，深圳封城，同样的悲剧为什么要一次次重复上演？难道润是普通百姓的唯一选择？</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half a story</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220420/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 12:05:52 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220420/</guid>
      <description>I have been to several cities in my travel.
I lived in a city when I was young. In the north, there&amp;rsquo;s my childhood in a rural village and a high school. In the east, that&amp;rsquo;s my home for a while. In the west, I had my best college time. In the south, that&amp;rsquo;s where my girlfriend lived. At that time, the city was still small. I could walk to my grandma&amp;rsquo;s house on my little feet from my school.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solidarity with Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220417/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 13:16:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220417/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;It is unreal to watch some alleged leftists, in real time, fail to recognise a fascist dictatorship attempting to exterminate a liberal democracy, and calling for that democracy to surrender to fascism in the name of peace.&amp;rdquo; I am with Oz Katerji on this.
If we agree Hitler invaded Poland, we have to agree Putin invaded Ukraine. If we stand with Ukraine, we have to send all resources including food, medcine, and arms to help Ukraine to defend themselves, till the victorious end.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What do we really love?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220415/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 10:17:11 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220415/</guid>
      <description>Went hiking to a nearby park. Bit cold and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty soon that my face was numbed. Birds sang their morning songs with no stop. On the top, the white peaks of rocky mountians in the west are clear to see. But no one to see but birds.
Memory is clearly somewhere in our brain. When we remember something, it&amp;rsquo;s somehow printed hard there. If you practise, anything like jogging, swimming, basketball, guitar, violin, or piano, you know how the muscle memory is there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Half of a Story</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220411/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 16:04:26 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220411/</guid>
      <description>I still do not know what is the best way to say goodbye. I hate it. So all the time, I evaded them because they were sad. Upon graduation, I did not send my friends off. Leaving my hometown, I left alone. No one taught me, I just tried it out slowly as life moves on. I have so many things to say. But where to start?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>double standard</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220410/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 14:03:30 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220410/</guid>
      <description>Double standard is everywhere in our life. The difference between I and others. The difference between my family and others. The difference between my people and others.
President Zelensky is leading a fight not only for defending Ukraine but the freedom of western values. He is a hero. But if we are serious, we have to deal with the double standard. Besides Kyiv, how about other cities like Baghdad, or Kabul?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Noam Chomsky Interview</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220406/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:50:52 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220406/</guid>
      <description>At the age of 93, Chomsky told us, &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re approaching the most dangerous point in human history &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s monstrous for Ukraine.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;It’s certainly right to have moral outrage about Putin’s actions in Ukraine,” he said of Biden’s recent declaration that the Russian president “cannot remain in power”. “But it would be even more progress to have moral outrage about other horrible atrocities… In Afghanistan, literally millions of people are facing imminent starvation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another C Code Joke</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220327/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 14:07:29 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220327/</guid>
      <description>$ pcat goes-to.c #include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt; int main() { int x = 5; // while x goes to 0: while (x --&amp;gt; 0) { printf(&amp;#34;%d &amp;#34;, x); } printf(&amp;#34;\n&amp;#34;); return 0; } $ gcc goes-to.c &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ./a.out 4 3 2 1 0 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Freud&#39;s single greatest contribution?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220323/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 20:04:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220323/</guid>
      <description>Freud already answered this question, of course, when he said that whereas Darwin decentered the human animal from the apex of creation, Copernicus decentered the earth from the center of the universe, Freud had decentered humanity in itself. No longer was the human immanent.
Lacan&amp;rsquo;s answer is perhaps even better: &amp;ldquo;That is why the unconscious was invented—so that we would realize that man&amp;rsquo;s desire is the Other&amp;rsquo;s desire, and that love, while it is a passion that involves ignorance of desire, nevertheless leaves desire its whole import&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rebuild</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/rebuild/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 15:16:56 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/rebuild/</guid>
      <description>how to build this hugo site</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C Code Jokes</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220318/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 15:22:58 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220318/</guid>
      <description>Here are some C code with the JavaScript quirks. Credits to luna.
#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt; int main() { puts(&amp;#34;-0.5&amp;#34; + 1); printf(&amp;#34;%d\n&amp;#34;, 50 ** &amp;#34;2&amp;#34;); return 0; } To build and run the above code, just do the following and ignore the warnings.
$ gcc c-js.c &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ./a.out 0.5 2500 Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the warnings first.
c-js.c:4:15: warning: adding &amp;#39;int&amp;#39; to a string does not append to the string [-Wstring-plus-int] puts(&amp;#34;-0.5&amp;#34; + 1); ~~~~~~~^~~ c-js.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fish and Pond</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220306/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 14:38:20 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220306/</guid>
      <description>Think of your mind like a pond full of fish and each fish is a feeling. Try to be the pond, not the fish.
Life is nothing but time given to us, short or long. For all of us, a day is long and a year is short. We use our days to trade for years. We trade our time for food, clothes, houses and cars. In the end, time is the only thing we do not have.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toit Imports</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220303/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 14:44:04 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220303/</guid>
      <description>Toitlang uses import to use code from other libraries.
local import starting with . $ tree . └── my_lib ├── my_lib.toit ├── other.toit └── sub └── sub.toit Assume we are importing sub.toit into my_lib.toit.
import .sub.sub Shorten version:
import .sub global import import math Then for customizations,
import math as m import math show sin cos </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cron is fun</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220302/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 14:21:56 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220302/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading Toit Code (002)</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220301/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 14:47:53 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220301/</guid>
      <description>After toit_start(), we have toit_esp32.cc to read. The first one is toit::start(). Toit here is just a namespace. As we know that toit supports OTA (over-the-air update) through WiFi and esp32 device is set to be a station (STA instead of AP).
What we have here is as follows:
RtcMemory::set_up(); FlashRegistry::set_up(); OS::set_up(); esp_partition_find_first(); setup_program(support_ota); Scheduler::ExitState exit_state; VM vm; vm.load_platform_event_sources(); int groud_id = vm.scheduler()-&amp;gt;next_group_id(); exit_state = vm.scheduler()-&amp;gt;run_boot_program(program, null, group_id); OS::tear_down(); FlashRegistry::tear_down(); After these, esp32 may go to deep sleep.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading Toit Code (001)</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220225/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 14:51:27 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220225/</guid>
      <description>When I started to port the code to ESP32S3 following the example of ESP32C3, I realized I had to read the code closely. Here are the notes along the way.
Where does the code get started on esp32? Based on esp-idf, Toit (I like to pronounce it as tight) creates a new platform with a new programming language for developers.
For the code to start on the esp32 device, check all the files inside toolchains/esp32/.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invasion!</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220221/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 14:55:05 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220221/</guid>
      <description>Today Putin ordered troops into pro-Russian region of eastern Ukraine in the name of peacekeeping. Ukraine invaded.
Then I saw the news of Dr. Paul Farmer. “The idea that some lives matter less is the root of all that is wrong with the world.”</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infinite Dead</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220204/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 14:57:08 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220204/</guid>
      <description>I remember once offering to an editor an article which began with a reference to the experience of last century. “Oh,” he said, “leave out the history and come to the present.” I felt like going to him over a thousand miles and taking him by the lapels and saying, “Dear, dear jackass! Don’t you understand that the past is the present; that without what was, nothing is? That, of the infinite dead, the living are but unimportant bits?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do not ask your children</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220203/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 14:59:21 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220203/</guid>
      <description>Do not ask your children
to strive for extraordinary lives.
Such striving may seem admirable,
but it is the way of foolishness.
Help them instead to find the wonder
and the marvel of an ordinary life.
Show them the joy of tasting
tomatoes, apples and pears.
Show them how to cry
when pets and people die.
Show them the infinite pleasure
in the touch of a hand.
And make the ordinary come alive for them</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>reading experience</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220129/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 15:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220129/</guid>
      <description>“People without hope not only don’t write novels, but what is more to the point, they don’t read them. They don’t take long looks at anything, because they lack the courage. The way to despair is to refuse to have any kind of experience, and the novel, of course, is a way to have experience. The lady who only read books that improved her mind was taking a safe course - and a hopeless one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mindful and calm</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220125/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 15:03:32 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220125/</guid>
      <description>The good and the bad are everywhere all the time. While reading stories and watching movies there are always heroes and villains in these endless dramas. There are always Don Quixote and Sancho. What am I? What are you? A mixture of good and bad. That’s all. What if we stop dividing us into black and white?
One teaching of Budha is now and here. What does it mean? No regret and guilty for the past.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use Jaguar to update</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220117/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 15:05:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220117/</guid>
      <description>Use an Airport to setup a WiFi network. Then download the binary of Jaguar. Run the following commands one after another. The second command requires the WiFi credentials. Use CTRL+C to stop the third one. To run the forth and the fifth command, put your computer on the same WiFi network as the esp32 device.
$./jag setup $./jag flash $./jag monitor $./jag scan $./jag run hello.toit </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>wasm3 on esp32</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220116/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 15:11:45 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220116/</guid>
      <description>Stumbled on this repo.
Run the modified code on one snowflake with 25 RGB LEDs (ws2812b-2020).
Check the video tweet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toit on m5core2</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220115/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 15:13:45 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220115/</guid>
      <description>Build some examples in toit and flash it to M5Core2.
There is no problem to follow the steps in one toit discussion. While trying the step4 for ft63xx. Found a typo in package.yaml. mpu6886 should be ft63xx.
Another issue is that the touch seems not working after unplugging the USB cable. Will investigate further. Will try jaguar tool later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rust on esp32</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220111/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 15:18:20 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220111/</guid>
      <description>Start to look at the toolchain for Rust on ESP32 family modules. After some googling, here is the first result.
Clearly the toolchain is working in its early stage. $ cargo build OK. Both espflash and espmonitor are working.
Reference:
Rust on ESP32 rust esp32 std demo </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mass delusion</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220108/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 15:23:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220108/</guid>
      <description>“Of special importance is the case in which substantial numbers of people, acting in concert, try to assure themselves of happiness and protection against suffering through a delusional reshaping of reality. The religions of mankind too must be described as example of mass delusion. Of course, no one who still shares a delusion will ever recognize it as such.”
“We never have so little protection against suffering as when we are in love; we are never so desolate when we have lost the object of our love or its love for us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I write</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20211224/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 15:24:34 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20211224/</guid>
      <description>Had my credentials been in order I would never have become a writer. Had I been blessed with even limited access to my own mind there would have been no reason to write. I write entirely to find out what I’m thinking, what I’m looking at, what I see and what it means. What I want and what I fear. Why did the oil refineries around Carquinez Strait seem sinister to me in the summer of 1956?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emily Dickinson</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20211212/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 14:34:21 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20211212/</guid>
      <description>In this short Life that only lasts an hour
How much - how little - is within our power</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>友谊是什么</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20211101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 19:39:10 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20211101/</guid>
      <description>这是旧作重发。
如果你读了我那些关于人性之双重性的笔记，你或许会喜欢诗人David Whyte关于友谊的观点：
友谊的根本不在于改善，不是你变好，也不是她（他）变好。友谊的根本在于见证，一种被人关注的特权，同时也与人以关注特权，且行、且看、且信任，有时仅只陪伴，旅途或许短暂，却不可能一人独自行走。
The poet David Whyte said that &amp;ldquo;the ultimate touchstone of friendship is not improvement, neither of the other nor of the self. The ultimate touchstone is witness, the privilege of having been seen by someone, and the equal privilege of being granted the sight of the essence of another, to have walked with them, and to have believed in them, and sometimes, just to have accompanied them, for however brief a span, on a journey impossible to accomplish alone.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
