<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Jean-Luc Godard on un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/jean-luc-godard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jean-Luc Godard on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.146.7</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 08:32:40 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/jean-luc-godard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Loneliness</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220912/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 08:32:40 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220912/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An excerpt from Deleuze on Godard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can tell you how I think of Godard. He&amp;rsquo;s a man who works very hard, and it follows that he is completely alone. But this loneliness is not the common sort: it&amp;rsquo;s filled by a huge assortment of things. Not dreams, fantasies or projects, but actions, things and even people. It is a many-faceted, creative loneliness. It&amp;rsquo;s what lies behind Godard&amp;rsquo;s ability to operate powerfully on his own, but also as part of a team. He can deal on equal terms with anyone, with big organizations or the powers that be, with a cleaning lady, a manual worker or the insane. In the television programmes, Godard&amp;rsquo;s questions are always straight. They trouble us, the viewers, but not the people they are addressed to. He speaks to the insane in a way which is not that of a psychiatrist or that of a fellow madman or someone pretending to be one. He speaks with workers without being a a boss or another worker or an intellectual or a film director with actors. This is not because he can switch his manner to suit the occasion, because he is a skillful operator, but because his loneliness somehow opens him up to anyone and everything. In a way, it&amp;rsquo;s always a question of stammering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
