<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Language on un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/language/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Language on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.125.7</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 06:39:02 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>the world versus me</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240906/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 06:39:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240906/</guid>
      <description>This is from a tweet: knowing about architecture means buildings are legible in a different way; knowing about plants and birds makes hikes more stimulating, playing music makes listening to it richer, etc.
However, it clicks with me from another perspective. To understand or to know the world better, we have to know some details and have to know it in one or many more abstracted ways. Yes, the world (so vast in both time and space) to us (so tiny, life is so short) is always abstracted one way or another for us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the power of words, and narratives</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240708/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 10:50:21 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240708/</guid>
      <description>Again and again Bachmann shows how “the flawed language that has been passed onto us” can lead us to question what we know to be real, our own suffering selves included, and she asks what it means to grapple with these antinomies of world and word as public and political matters, not just private ones—indeed what it means to be a writer at all. “If we had the word, if we had language, we would not need weapons,” she said in a 1959 lecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>even if you don&#39;t cheat, life cheats you anyway</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230423/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 08:50:10 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230423/</guid>
      <description>The title is a line from Lynn in the 2017 Thai movie, Bad Genius. &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t you see &amp;ndash; even if you don&amp;rsquo;t cheat, life cheats you anyway.&amp;rdquo;
When I learn English, the literal meaning is easy to get but the subtle culture and personal feel is hard to grasp. This can come to the difference between two persons. What do I know what you say means the same as I say the same words and sentences?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>walter benjamin</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230205/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 18:38:05 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230205/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;In modernist art, obscurity can be a conscious strategy. It is one of the ways in which the artwork can avoid being consumed too easily. Poems need to thicken their textures and scramble their syntax if they are not to slip down too easily, which is the fate of the commodity. Everyday language is no longer a medium of truth. It has grown stale and threadbare, and only by wreaking violence on it can you force it to yield something of value.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
