<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Kant on un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/kant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kant on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.125.7</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:36:27 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/kant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kant Critique of pure reason by Robert Paul wolff</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250108/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:36:27 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250108/</guid>
      <description>Start to read the blog of Robert Paul wolff. Start to watch his lectures on Kant.
video blog part 1 Reading the Critique Part I part 2 reading the Critique Part II part 3 reading the Critique Part III part 4 reading the Critique part IV part 5 reading the Critique part V part 6 reading the Critique part VI part 7 reading the Critique part VII part 8 reading the critique part VIII part 9 reading the Critique part IX From the wiki page: Kant builds on the work of empiricist philosophers such as John Locke and David Hume, as well as rationalist philosophers such as Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz and Christian Wolff.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are the ever-changing you still yourself?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220520/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 09:42:06 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220520/</guid>
      <description>Kant has four big questions for philosophy.
What can I know? How should I act? For what can I hope? What is the human being? This writing has something to do with Kant&amp;rsquo;s last question.
In the book of &amp;ldquo;Last Chance to See&amp;rdquo;, Douglas Adams told an anecdote about the Golden Pavilion Temple in Kyoto.
&amp;ldquo;I remembered once, in Japan, having been to see the Gold Pavilion Temple in Kyoto and being mildly surprised at quite how well it had weathered the passage of time sicne it was first built in the fourteenth century.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
