<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Kafka on un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/kafka/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kafka on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.125.7</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:02:25 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/kafka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>reading</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250116/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:02:25 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20250116/</guid>
      <description>our real work Our real work Wendell Berry, 1983 It may be that when we no longer know what to do We have come to our real work, And that when we no longer know which way to go We have come to our real journey. The mind that is not baffled is not employed. The impeded stream is the one that sings. the following is all about reading &amp;ldquo;If you think about it, the very best books are really just extremely long spells that turn you into a different person for the rest of your life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes on 20240321</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240321/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 15:34:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240321/</guid>
      <description>The world I live in Mary Oliver I have refused to live locked in the orderly house of reasons and proofs. The world I live in and believe in is wider than that. And anyway, what’s wrong with Maybe? You wouldn’t believe what once or twice I have seen. I’ll just tell you this: only if there are angels in your head will you ever, possibly, see one. A book must be an ice axe to break the sea frozen inside us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the world and our mind</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231110/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 20:32:51 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20231110/</guid>
      <description>marcel proust (1871-1922): We fall in love for a smile, a look, a shoulder. That is enough; then, in the long hours of hope or sorrow, we fabricate a person, we compose a character. And when later on we see much of the beloved person, we can no longer, whatever the cruel reality that confronts us, strip off that good character, that nature of a woman who loves us, from the person who bestows that glance, bares that shoulder, than we can when she has grown old eliminate her youthful face from a person whom we have known since her girlhood.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
