<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>history on un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in history on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 19:57:45 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>history, the rich, and Tim Jacob Wise</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230719/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 19:57:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230719/</guid>
      <description>Divided and conquered. It is not just in America, it is quite everywhere?! Imagine that the whiteness is created by the rich for the poor, in America. Then the Redness is created by the power for the powerless, in China.
Tim Wise Part 3 the history of whiteness</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>different forms of power?</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230416/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 10:15:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20230416/</guid>
      <description>In my backyard, there are always bird dramas going on and on. As you may know that birds are territorial animals. One year, a robin couple fought with another couple of black crow because somehow the black crow stole their chick and ate it. the poor robins called all their friends and had a fight on the garage&amp;rsquo;s roof. This spring, two Magpies built their nest on the apple tree. The construction took about a month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folly&#39;s Antidote</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220818/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 17:59:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220818/</guid>
      <description>Folly&amp;rsquo;s Antidote But all historians are prisoners of their own experience. We bring to history the preconceptions of our personalities and of our age. We cannot seize on ultimate and absolute truths. So the historian is committed to a doomed enterprise &amp;ndash; the quest for an unattainable objectivity.
Conceptions of the past are far from stable. They are perennially revised by the urgencies of the present. When new urgencies arise in our own times and lives, the historian&amp;rsquo;s soptlight shifts, probing at last into the darkness, throwing into sharp relief things that were always there but that earlier historians had carelessly excised from the collective memory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
