<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>story on un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/story/</link>
    <description>Recent content in story on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 13:36:35 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>the power of words and stories</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221107/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 13:36:35 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20221107/</guid>
      <description>It is easy to forget how mysterious and mighty stories are. They do their work in silence, invisibly. They work with all the internal meterials of your mind and self. They become part of you while changing you. Beware the stories you read or tell; subtly, at night, beneath the waters of consciousness, they are altering your world.
&amp;ndash; Ben Okri
Ben Okri was born in 1959. In 1991, he won the Booker Prize with his novel The Famished Road.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>me and you</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220506/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 09:16:58 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220506/</guid>
      <description>At a night with stars, you and I, may see a similar sky. At a day with sunshine, you and I, may see a different city. I am not sure what your city is. My city is so small and it has three grocery stores, two clinics, one children hospital, four schools, one library, two gas stations, a few parks and a river. Three remote cities still in my memory. Plus a few colleagues and friends.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vorld</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220501/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 19:48:27 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220501/</guid>
      <description>vorld Vorld is a personal world. V is just a half of W. In your time, the people you have met, the places you have been, the things you have done, these are your vorld. Just a small part of the world.
desire Lacan has a famous dictum, man’s desire is the desire of the Other. What you want, in the end, is a construct by the vorld from the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>旧作重读</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220425/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 10:39:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220425/</guid>
      <description>“人造之物皆有生命。”记不得是在哪里看到这段话，“语言自然而生，文化随之而来。建房修葺，修路搭桥，这些不都是生命的延展？学校教堂医院，警局政府法院，这些不都是生命的附属？“</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half a story</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220420/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 12:05:52 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220420/</guid>
      <description>I have been to several cities in my travel.
I lived in a city when I was young. In the north, there&amp;rsquo;s my childhood in a rural village and a high school. In the east, that&amp;rsquo;s my home for a while. In the west, I had my best college time. In the south, that&amp;rsquo;s where my girlfriend lived. At that time, the city was still small. I could walk to my grandma&amp;rsquo;s house on my little feet from my school.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Half of a Story</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220411/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 16:04:26 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220411/</guid>
      <description>I still do not know what is the best way to say goodbye. I hate it. So all the time, I evaded them because they were sad. Upon graduation, I did not send my friends off. Leaving my hometown, I left alone. No one taught me, I just tried it out slowly as life moves on. I have so many things to say. But where to start?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
