<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Understand on un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/understand/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Understand on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.146.7</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 06:39:02 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/notes/tags/understand/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>the world versus me</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240906/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 06:39:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20240906/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is from &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/economeager/status/1830271859671327153&#34;&gt;a tweet&lt;/a&gt;: knowing about architecture means buildings are legible in a different way; knowing about plants and birds makes hikes more stimulating, playing music makes listening to it richer, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it clicks with me from another perspective. To understand or to know the world better, we have to know some details and have to know it in one or many more abstracted ways. Yes, the world (so vast in both time and space) to us (so tiny, life is so short) is always abstracted one way or another for us. For example, the capitalism is an abstracted construct in the real world. It is there for real and abstracted. Sometimes, we know it. Sometimes we know its name only. Sometimes we do not know its name yet but just feel its existance like the elephant to the blind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>liberty and freedom</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220525/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 09:21:20 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/notes/posts/20220525/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday 21 people were killed in an attack by a lone gunman at an elementary school in Uvalde, Texas. The 18-year-old gunman was killed by police. Why tragedies like this happen again and again in the United States? Buffalo, Laguna  Woods, Sandy hook, Santa Fe High, El Paso, and so many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March 13, 1996. 26 years ago, a gunman entered Dunblane Primary School in Scotland, killed 16 kids and a teacher. The UK government responded by enacting tight gun control legislation. Since then there has been a total of zero school shootings in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
